<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER III</Header>
        <Name>PRIVILEGES AND IMMUNITIES, DIPLOMATIC AND CONSULAR RELATIONS, ETC</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>11</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Vienna Convention on the Representation of States in their Relations with International Organizations of a Universal Character</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Vienna, 14 March 1975</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>see article 89 which reads as follows: "1. The present Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day following the date of deposit of the thirty-fifth instrument of ratification or accession. 2. For each State ratifying or acceding to the Convention after the deposit of the thirty-fifth instrument of ratification or accession, the Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after the deposit of such State of its instrument of ratification or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>20</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>34</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/a_conf.67_16-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt; A/CONF.67/16&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted on 13 March 1975 by the United Nations Conference on the Representation of States in their Relations with International Organizations held at the Neue Hofburg in Vienna, Austria, from 4 February to 14 March 1975. The Convention was opened for signature at Vienna on 14 March 1975 at the Federal Ministry for Foreign Affairs of the Republic of Austria. After 30 September 1975, it remained open for signature at the United Nations Headquarters in New York until 30 March 1976, the closing date for signature.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
