<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER IV</Header>
        <Name>HUMAN RIGHTS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>9</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>b</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Optional Protocol to the Convention against Torture and Other Cruel, Inhuman or Degrading Treatment or Punishment</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>New York, 18 December 2002</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>22 June 2006, in accordance with article 28(1) which reads as follows: "1. The present Protocol shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after the date of deposit with the Secretary-General of the United Nations of the twentieth instrument of ratification or accession. 2. For each State ratifying the present Protocol or acceding to it after the deposit with the Secretary-General of the United Nations of the twentieth instrument of ratification or accession, the present Protocol shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after the date of deposit of its own instrument of ratification or accession".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>22 June 2006, No. 24841</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>75</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>87</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2375, p. 237; GA Resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_57_199-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/57/199&lt;/a&gt; of 9 January 2003. C.N.25.2010.TREATIES-1 of 29 January 2010 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Optional Protocol (authentic Russian and Spanish texts) and to the certified true copies; C.N.244.2010.TREATIES-3 of 30 April 2010 (Corrections to the original text of the Optional Protocol (authentic Russian and Spanish texts) and to the certified true copies.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The above Protocol was adopted on 18 December 2002 at the fifty-seventh session of the General Assembly of the United Nations by resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_57_199-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/57/199&lt;/a&gt;. In accordance with article 27 (1), the Protocol was opened for signature on 4 February 2003, the first possible date, by any State that has signed the Convention. In accordance with operative paragraph 1 of General Assembly resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_57_199-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/57/199&lt;/a&gt;, the Protocol is available for signature, ratification and accession at United Nations Headquarters in New York.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
