<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER IX</Header>
        <Name>HEALTH</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>4</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol to Eliminate Illicit Trade in Tobacco Products</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Seoul, 12 November 2012</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>Article 45: 1. This Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day following the date of deposit of the fortieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval, formal confirmation or accession with the Depositary. 2. For each Party to the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control that ratifies, accepts, approves or formally confirms this Protocol or accedes thereto after the conditions set out in paragraph 1 for entry into force have been fulfilled, this Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day following the date of deposit of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval, accession or formal confirmation. 3. For the purposes of this Article, any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by States Members of that organization.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>54</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>34</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>The above Protocol, which was adopted during the fifth session of the Conference of the Parties to the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control by Decision &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/FCTC_COP5_REC1_150413_COMPLETE.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;FCTC/COP5 (1)&lt;/a&gt; of 12 November 2012, will be open for signature at a signing ceremony to be held in Geneva, Switzerland, from 10 to 11 January 2013 and, thereafter, at United Nations Headquarters in New York.</Text>
          <Text>In accordance with its article 43, the Protocol shall be open for signature by all Parties to the WHO Framework Convention on Tobacco Control at World Health Organization Headquarters in Geneva from 10 to 11 January 2013, and thereafter at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 9 January 2014.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote />
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="3">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Approval(AA), Acceptance(A), Accession(a), Ratification, Formal confirmation(c)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Austria</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry>28 Oct 2014</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belgium</Entry>
                <Entry>17 May 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Benin</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Botswana</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Oct 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Burkina Faso</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Mar 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Mar 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>China</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Colombia</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Feb 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Comoros</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>14 Oct 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Congo</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>14 May 2015 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Costa Rica</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Mar 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>7 Mar 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Côte d'Ivoire</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>25 May 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cyprus</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Oct 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Aug 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Democratic Republic of the Congo</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Dec 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Denmark</Entry>
                <Entry>7 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ecuador</Entry>
                <Entry>25 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>15 Oct 2015</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>European Union</Entry>
                <Entry>20 Dec 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Jun 2016 c</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Fiji</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Jul 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Finland</Entry>
                <Entry>25 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>France</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Nov 2015</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Gabon</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Oct 2014 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Gambia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>26 Sep 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Germany</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Oct 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>31 Oct 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ghana</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Greece</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Jul 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Guinea</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 May 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Guinea-Bissau</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Iran (Islamic Republic of)</Entry>
                <Entry>7 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Iraq</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>2 Dec 2015 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ireland</Entry>
                <Entry>20 Dec 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Israel</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Dec 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Kenya</Entry>
                <Entry>29 May 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Kuwait</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Nov 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Latvia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>4 Feb 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Libya</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lithuania</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>14 Dec 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Madagascar</Entry>
                <Entry>25 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Sep 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Mali</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry>17 Jun 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Mongolia</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Nov 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Oct 2014</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Montenegro</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Jul 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Oct 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Myanmar</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Netherlands</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Nicaragua</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>20 Dec 2013</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Niger</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>12 Jul 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Norway</Entry>
                <Entry>16 Oct 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Panama</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Sep 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Portugal</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Jul 2015</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Qatar</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Jun 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Republic of Korea</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Saudi Arabia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Oct 2015 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Senegal</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>31 Aug 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Serbia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>30 Jun 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Slovakia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>25 Sep 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Slovenia</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>South Africa</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Spain</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>23 Dec 2014 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sri Lanka</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>8 Feb 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sudan</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Swaziland</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Sep 2016 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sweden</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Syrian Arab Republic</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Togo</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Tunisia</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Turkey</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Turkmenistan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>30 Mar 2015 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</Entry>
                <Entry>17 Dec 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United Republic of Tanzania</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2013</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Uruguay</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jan 2013</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Sep 2014</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Yemen</Entry>
                <Entry>7 Jan 2014</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations were made upon</Title>
      <Title>ratification, acceptance, approval, formal confirmation or accession.)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Costa Rica</Participant>
        <text type="title">Interpretative declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">In the case of the Republic of Costa Rica, for the purposes of the implementation of article 27 of the Protocol, the Ministries of the Treasury, Public Health, Economic Affairs, Trade and Industry, the Interior and Police, and Public Security shall be responsible for proposing any amendments to domestic laws, regulations and rules in general that might be required for compliance with this Protocol, within their competencies and powers, and without prejudice to the constitutional powers vested in the legislative and executive branches.</text>
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>European Union</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration pursuant to article 44:</text>
        <text type="para">The European Union (EU) submits, in accordance with Article 44 of the Protocol to Eliminate Illicit Trade in Tobacco Products to the World Health Organisation's Framework Convention on Tobacco Control ("FCTC Protocol"), the following Declaration of Competences specifying the categories and policy areas in respect of which the Member States of the EU have conferred competences upon the EU in the areas covered by the FCTC Protocol.</text>
        <text type="para">1. General Principles</text>
        <text type="para">The categories and areas of Union competence are set out in Articles 2 to 6 TFEU. When the Treaties confer on the EU exclusive competence in a specific area, only the EU may legislate and adopt legally binding acts, the Member States being able to do so themselves only if so empowered by the EU or for the implementation of EU acts. When the Treaties confer on the EU a competence shared with the Member States in a specific area, the EU and the Member States may legislate and adopt legally binding acts in that area. The Member States shall exercise their competence to the extent that the EU has not exercised its competence. The Member States shall again exercise their competence to the extent that the EU has decided to cease exercising its competence.</text>
        <text type="para">As regards the conclusion of international agreements, for the policy areas listed in Article 3(1) TFEU, only the EU has the competence to act. For the policy areas listed in Article 4(2) TFEU the EU and its Member States share competence, but only the EU has the competence to act when the envisaged action is necessary to enable the Union to exercise its internal competence, or insofar as the provisions in the agreement may affect common rules or alter their scope within the meaning of Article 3(2) TFEU; insofar as this isnot the case (i.e. the conditions of Article 3(2) TFEU are not met), Member States may exercise their competence to act in these policy areas.</text>
        <text type="para">Competences not attributed to the EU by the Treaties fall within the competences of the Member States of the EU.</text>
        <text type="para">The EU will duly notify any substantial modification of the extent of its competences, in accordance with Article 44 of the Protocol, without this constituting a prerequisite for the exercise of its competence in matters covered by the FCTC Protocol.</text>
        <text type="para">2. Exclusive competence of the EU</text>
        <text type="para">2.1. The EU has exclusive competence to act with respect to the matters covered by the FCTC Protocol that fall under the scope of the common commercial policy of the EU (Article 207 TFEU).</text>
        <text type="para">2.2. In addition, the EU has exclusive competence to act with regard to matters covered by the FCTC protocol that fall under the scope of customs cooperation (Article 33 TFEU), approximation of laws in the internal market (Articles 113 and 114 TFEU), judicial cooperation in criminal matters (Article 82 TFEU) and definition of criminal offences (Article 83 TFEU), only insofar as the provisions of a Union act establish common rules that may be affected or altered in scope by provisions of the FCTC protocol.</text>
        <text type="para">The list of Union acts below illustrates the extent to which the Union has exercised its internal competence in these fields in accordance with the Treaty on the Functioning of the European Union. The extent of Union exclusive competence ensuing from these acts must be assessed by reference to the precise provisions of each measure, and in particular the extent to which these provisions establish common rules that risk to be affected or altered in scope by the provisions of the FCTC Protocol or an act adopted in implementation thereof.</text>
        <text type="para"> Directive 2014/40/EU of the European Parliament and of the Council of 3 April 2014 on the approximation of the laws, regulations and administrative provisions of the Member States concerning the manufacture, presentation and sale of tobacco and related products and repealing Directive 2001/37/EC (OJ L 127, 29.4.2014, p. 1);</text>
        <text type="para"> Directive 2005/60/EC of the European Parliament and of the Council of 26 October 2005 on the prevention of the use of the financial system for the purpose of money laundering and terrorist financing (OJ L 309, 25.11.2005, p. 15);</text>
        <text type="para"> Regulation (EU) No 952/2013 of the European Parliament and of the Council of 9 October 2013 laying down the Union Customs Code (OJ L 269, 10.10.2013, p. 1);</text>
        <text type="para"> Council Directive 2008/118/EC of 16 December 2008 concerning the general arrangements for excise duty and repealing Directive 92/12/EEC (OJ L 9, 14.1.2009, p. 12);</text>
        <text type="para"> Council Directive 2011/64/EU of 21 June 2011 on the structure and rates of excise duty applied to manufactured tobacco (OJ L 176, 5.7.2011, p. 24);</text>
        <text type="para"> Council Framework Decision 2001/500/JHA of 26 June 2001 on money laundering, the identification, tracing, freezing, seizing and confiscation of instrumentalities and the proceeds of crime (OJ L 182, 5.7.2001, p. 1);</text>
        <text type="para"> Council Act of 26 July 1995 drawing up the Convention on the protection of the European Communities' financial interests (OJ C 316, 27.11.1995, p. 48).</text>
        <text type="para">3. Competence of the Member States</text>
        <text type="para">For other matters covered by the FCTC Protocol not mentioned in sections 2.1 and 2.2, for which the EU has not exclusive competence to act, the Member States remain competent to act.</text>
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="NO" />
    <EndNotes />
    <Footer>IX 4 a. Health</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
