<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER VI</Header>
        <Name>NARCOTIC DRUGS AND PSYCHOTROPIC SUBSTANCES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>11</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Convention for the Suppression of the Illicit Traffic in Dangerous Drugs</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 26 June 1936, and Lake Success, New York, 11 December 1946&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>10 October 1947, the date on which the amendments to the Convention, as set forth in the annex to the Protocol of 11 December 1946, entered into force, in accordance with paragraph 2 of article VII of the Protocol.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>26 October 1939, No. 4648</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>League of Nations, Treaty Series, vol. 198, p. 301.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote />
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="3">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Definitive signature of the Protocol, Acceptance of the Protocol</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Ratification of the Convention as amended, Accession to the Convention as amended(a)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Austria</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>17 May 1950</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belgium</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Brazil</Entry>
                <Entry>17 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cambodia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>3 Oct 1951 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cameroon</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>15 Jan 1962 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Canada</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Chile</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Nov 1972 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>China&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Colombia</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Côte d'Ivoire</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>20 Dec 1961 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cuba</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Aug 1967</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Dominican Republic</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Jun 1958 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Egypt</Entry>
                <Entry>13 Sep 1948</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ethiopia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Sep 1947 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>France</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Oct 1947</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Greece</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Feb 1949</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Haiti</Entry>
                <Entry>31 May 1951</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>India</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Indonesia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>3 Apr 1958 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Israel</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>16 May 1952 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Italy</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>3 Apr 1961 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Japan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>7 Sep 1955</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Jordan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>7 May 1958 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lao People's Democratic Republic</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>13 Jul 1951 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Liechtenstein</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>24 May 1961 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Luxembourg</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>28 Jun 1955 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Madagascar</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>11 Dec 1974 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Malawi</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>8 Jun 1965 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Mexico</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>6 May 1955</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Netherlands&lt;superscript&gt;3,4&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>[19 Mar 1959 ]</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Romania</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Oct 1961</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Rwanda</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>15 Jul 1981 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Spain&lt;superscript&gt;5&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>5 Jun 1970</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sri Lanka</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>4 Dec 1957 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Switzerland</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>31 Dec 1952</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Turkey</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Dec 1946</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations and Reservations</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations and reservations were made</Title>
      <Title>upon ratification or accession.)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Cuba</Participant>
        <text type="para">The Revolutionary Government of the Republic of Cuba expressly reserves its position on the provisions of article 17 of the Convention, being ready to settle any dispute which may arise on the interpretation or application of the Convention bilaterally, by means of diplomatic consultations.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Italy</Participant>
        <text type="para">. . . In exercise of the right accorded to it by article 13, paragraph 2, of the said Convention, the Government of Italy desires that, in the case of letters of request concerning narcotic drugs, the procedure hitherto followed in previous relations with the other Contracting States should continue to be used and, failing that, the diplomatic channel, provided, however, that the method specified in article 13, paragraph 1, sub-paragraph (c) should be adopted in cases of emergency.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Mexico</Participant>
        <text type="para">In accepting the provisions of articles 11 and 12 of this Convention, the Government of the United States of Mexico wishes to state explicitly that its Central Office will exercise the powers granted to it by the said Convention unless such powers have been expressly conferred by the General Constitution of the Republic on an agency of a constituent State, being an agency established before the date of the entry into force of this Convention, and that the Government of the United States of Mexico reserves the right to impose in its territoryas it has already donemeasures more severe than those laid down by the Convention itself, for the restriction of the cultivation or the manufacture, extraction, possession, offering for sale, importation or exportation of or traffic in the drugs to which the present Convention refers.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="YES" />
    <EndNotes>
      <Note>
        <index>1</index>
        <text>The Agreement was amended by the Protocol signed at Lake Success, New York, on 11 December 1946.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>2</index>
        <text>See note concerning signatures, ratifications, accessions, etc., on behalf of China (note 1 under China in the Historical Information section in the front matter of this volume).</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>3</index>
        <text>The instrument of ratification stipulates that the Convention and the Protocol of signature will be applicable to the Kingdom in Europe, Surinam and the Netherlands New Guinea. In a communication received on 4 August 1960, the Government of the Netherlands notified the Secretary-General that the Convention will be applicable to the Netherlands Antilles. The ratification was made subject to the reservation recorded in the Protocol of Signature annexed to the Convention; for the text of that reservation, see United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol.327, p. 322.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>4</index>
        <text>In a communication received on 14 December 1965, the Government of the Kingdom of the Netherlands notified the Secretary-General of the denunciation of the Convention for the territory of the Kingdom in Europe and the Territories of Surinam and the Netherlands Antilles. The denunciation took effect on 14 December 1966.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>5</index>
        <text>Instrument of ratification of the unamended 1936 Convention. Spain, on behalf of which the Protocol of 11 December 1946 amending the Agreements, Conventions and Protocols on narcotic drugs concluded at The Hague on 23 January 1912, at Geneva on 11 February 1925, 19 February 1925 and 13 July 1931, at Bangkok on 27 November 1931 and at Geneva on 26 June 1936 was signed definitively on 26 September 1955 (see chapter VI.1), has, as a result of the said definitive signature and of its ratification of the unamended 1936 Convention, become a party to the said Convention of 1936 as amended by the said Protocol of 1946.</text>
      </Note>
    </EndNotes>
    <Footer>VI 11. Narcotic Drugs and Psychotropic Substances</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
