<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER X</Header>
        <Name>INTERNATIONAL TRADE AND DEVELOPMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>6</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Agreement establishing the Caribbean Development Bank</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kingston, 18 October 1969</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>26 January 1970, in accordance with article 64.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>26 January 1970, No. 10232</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>18</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>28</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 712, p. 217; vol. 1021, p. 437 (Addendum) [amendment to article 29 (1) (a)] and vol. 1401, p. 265 (amendments to articles 25, 33, 34, 35 and 57).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Agreement and Protocol were adopted by the Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Caribbean Development Bank which met at Kingston, Jamaica, on 18 October 1969. The Conference was convened for that purpose by the Acting Secretary-General of the Commonwealth Caribbean Regional Secretariat in accordance with the decision of the Commonwealth Caribbean Conference of Finance Ministers taken at its meeting held at Port of Spain, Trinidad and Tobago, on 22 July 1969. Both instruments were opened for signature by the Plenipotentiary Conference at Kingston on 18 October 1969. The Conference also adopted the Final Act, approved the memorandum of understanding relating to the allocation of the Bank's resources to multinational projects, which had been adopted by the Conference of Finance Ministers at Port of Spain, and adopted the resolution on the duties of the Trustee designated under article 7, paragraph (8), of the Agreement. The texts of the said memorandum and resolution are appended to the Final Act as annexes A and B.</Text>
          <Text>The Protocol, to provide for procedure for amendment of article 36 of the Agreement, became void, when the amendment proposed under the said procedure at the Inaugural Meeting of the Board of Governors of the Caribbean Development Bank, held at Nassau, Bahamas, on 31 January 1970, had failed to obtain the required majority.</Text>
          <Text>By Resolution No. 9/76 adopted on 20 August 1976, the Board of Governors of the Bank has amended article 29 (1) (a) of the Agreement (number of Directors) with effect from 2 September 1976.</Text>
          <Text>Subsequently, by Resolution No. 3/85 of 15 May 1985, the Board of Governors of the Bank adopted amendments to articles 25, 33, 34, 35 and 57 of the Agreement with effect from 24 June 1985.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
