<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XII</Header>
        <Name>NAVIGATION</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>3</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Convention relating to the unification of certain rules concerning collisions in inland navigation</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 15 March 1960</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>13 September 1966, in accordance with article 11which reads as follows: "1. This Convention shall come into force on the ninetieth day after five of the countries referred to in article 10, paragraph 1, have deposited their instruments of ratification or accession. 2. With respect to any country which ratifies the Convention or accedes to it after five countries have deposited their instruments of ratification or accession, this Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the said country has deposited its instrument of ratification or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>13 September 1966, No. 8310</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>5</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>13</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 572, p. 133.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was prepared by the Sub-Committee on Inland Water Transport of the Inland Transport Committee of the UnitedNations Economic Commission for Europe and its subsidiary bodies (Working Party on River Law and Groups of Rapporteurs). The Inland Transport Committee decided to open it for signature at its nineteenth session, held from 14 to 18 December 1959 (See Report of the Inland Transport Committee on its nineteenth session, document E/ECE/TRANS/514, para. 49).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
