<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XII</Header>
        <Name>NAVIGATION</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>7</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>United Nations Convention on Conditions for Registration of Ships</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 7 February 1986</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>see article 19 which reads as follows: "1. This Convention shall enter into force 12 months after the date on which not less than 40 States, the combined tonnage of which amounts to at least 25 per cent of the world tonnage, have become Contracting Parties to it in accordance with article 18. For the purpose of this article the tonnage shall be deemed to be that contained in annex III to this Convention. 2. For each State which becomes a Contracting Party to this Convention after the conditions for entry into force under paragraph 1 of this article have been met, the Convention shall enter into force for that State 12 months after that State has become a Contracting Party.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>14</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>15</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/TD_RS_CONF_19_Add.1_E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;TD/RS/CONF/19/Add.1&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/TD_RS_CONF_19_Add.1_Corr.1_E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;TD/RS/CONF/19/Add.1/Corr.1&lt;/a&gt;; depositary notifications C.N.131.1986.TREATIES-3 of 30 July?986 (procès-verbal of rectification of original Russian text) and C.N.246.1987.TREATIES-6 of 12 November 1987 (procès-verbal of rectification of original French text).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted by a Conference of plenipotentiaries which met at Geneva from 20 January to 7 February 1986 under the auspices of the UnitedNations Conference on Trade and Development, in accordance with resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/E_RES_37_209-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;37/209&lt;/a&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt; of the General Assembly of the United Nations dated 20 December 1982. The Conference on Conditions for Registration of Ships had held its first part from 16 July to 3 August 1984, and had resumed its work, first at its second part from 28 January to 15 February 1985 and then, at its third part from 8 to 19 July 1985, before adopting the Convention at its fourth and last part. Open for signature from 1 May 1986 to 30 April 1987 in New York.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
