<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XII</Header>
        <Name>NAVIGATION</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>1</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>d</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Amendments to the title and substantive provisions of the Convention on the International Maritime Organization</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>London, 14 November 1975 and 9 November 1977</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>22 May 1982 for all Members of the Organization, in accordance with article 51 of the Convention except for the amendment to article 51 which entered into force on 28 July 1982 in accordance with article 62 of the Convention as amended (Article 52, which was renumbered as Article 51 by Resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_315_ES.V-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;315 (ES.V)&lt;/a&gt; of 17 October 1974, is renumbered as Article 62 by Resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_358_IX-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A.358 (IX)&lt;/a&gt; of 14 November 1975)*.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>22 May 1982, No. 4214</Labeltext>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <CustomText>Parties*.</CustomText>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1276, p. 468; and vol. 1285, p. 318.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>See " &lt;i&gt;Note: &lt;/i&gt;" at beginning of chapter XII.1. </Text>
          <Text>The amendments were adopted by the Assembly of the Organization by resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_358_IX-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A.358 (IX)&lt;/a&gt; of 14 November 1975 and &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_371_X-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A.371?X)&lt;/a&gt; of 9 November 1977 [rectification of resolution A.358 (IX)].</Text>
          <Text>Note: Pursuant to article 53 of the Convention, the acceptance of an amendment shall be made by the communication of an instrument to the Secretary-General of the Organization for deposit with the Secretary-General of the United Nations.Following is the list of States which had accepted the Amendments to the Convention prior to their entry into force.</Text>
          <Text>*See chapter XII.1 for the complete list of Participants, Members of the International Maritime Organization, for which the above amendments are in force, pursuant to article 66 of the Convention as amended.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
