<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIV</Header>
        <Name>EDUCATIONAL AND CULTURAL MATTERS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>7</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Statutes of the International Centre for Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Madrid, 13 September 1983</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>3 February 1994, in accordance with article 21(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>3 February 1994, No. 30673</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>45</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>63</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol.?763, p.?1; see also hereinafter the Protocol of the reconvened plenipotentiary meeting (XIV.7a).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Statutes were adopted at the Ministerial Level Plenipotentiary Meeting on the Establishment of the International Centre for Genetic Engineering and Biotechnology held at Madrid, Spain, from 7 to 13 September 1983 under the auspices of the United Nations Industrial Development Organization. They were open for signature at Madrid on 12 and 13 September 1983 and remain open for signature at the United Nations Headquarters, New York, until their entry into force.</Text>
          <Text>Pursuant to article 21 (1), the Statutes are to enter into force when at least twenty-four States, including the Host State&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt; of the Centre, have deposited instruments of ratification or acceptance and having further ascertained among themselves that sufficient financial resources are ensured, have then deposited with the Secretary-General notifications indicating their agreement to the entry into force of the Statutes.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
