<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg3</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>21</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Agreement establishing the Common Fund for Commodities</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 27 June 1980</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>19 June 1989, in accordance with article 57(1)(see "Note.").</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>19 June 1989, No. 26691</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>111</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>113</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol.1538, p. 3.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Agreement was adopted on 27 June 1980 by the United Nations Negotiating Conference on a Common Fund under the Integrated Programme for Commodities, which met at Geneva from 5 to 27 June 1980 under the auspices of the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development (UNCTAD). The Agreement was opened for signature at the Headquarters of the United Nations, New York, on 1 October 1980, and will remain open for signature until one year after the date of its entry into force. At a meeting convened on 3 June 1982 in Geneva by the Secretary-General of UNCTAD, under article 57 (1) of the Agreement, the Contracting Parties decided to extend until 30 September 1983 the time-limit for the fulfilment of the requirements for its entry into force. Subsequently, by a later decision taken at a Meeting of those States which had deposited prior to 30 September 1983 an instrument of ratification, approval or acceptance, which was held on 19 June 1989, it was decided further to extend to 19 June 1989 [the date of the decision] the date by which the requirements should be fulfilled.</Text>
          <Text>Further, the Governing Council notifiied the Secretary-General of the following:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of receipt of the notification: Subject:&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text>11 November 2002 Establishment of conditions of accession by Costa Rica.</Text>
          <Text>20 November 2002 Establishment of conditions of accession by the Lao People's Democratic Republic.</Text>
          <Text>24 October 2005 Establishment of conditions of accession by the East African Community.</Text>
          <Text>26 March 2007 Establishment of conditions of accession by the Caribbean Community, the Econnomic Community of West African States, the Andean Community, the Southern African Development Communityand for Vanuatu.</Text>
          <Text>26 October 2007 Establishment of conditions of accession by the West African Economic and Monetary Union.</Text>
          <Text>4 February 2008 Establishment of conditions of accession for the West African Economic and Monetary Union.</Text>
          <Text>7 May 2009 Establishment of conditions of accession for the Economic Community of West African States.</Text>
          <Text>7 May 2009 Establishment of conditions of accession for the Eurasian Economic Community.</Text>
          <Text>7 May 2009 Establishment of conditions of accession for the West African Economic and Monetary Union.</Text>
          <Text>14 May 2009 Establishment of conditions of accession for Vanuatu.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
