<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>43</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>International Coffee Agreement 2001*</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>London, 28 September 2000</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>provisionally on 1 October 2001 and definitively on 17 May 2005, in accordance with article 45which reads as follows: "(1) This Agreement shall enter into force definitively on 1 October 2001 if by that date Governments representing at least 15 exporting Members holding at least 70 percent of the votes of the exporting Members and at least 10 importing Members holding at least 70 percent of the votes importing Members, calculated as at 25 September 2001, without reference to possible suspension under the terms of Articles 25 and 42, have deposited instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval. Alternatively, it shall enter into force definitively at any time after 1 October 2001 if it is provisionally in force in accordance with the provisons of paragraph (2) of this Article and these percentage requirements are satisfied by the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval. (2) This Agreement may enter into force provisionally on 1 October 2001. For this purpose, a notification by a signatory Government or by any other Contracting Party to the International Coffee Agreement 1994 as extended, containing an undertaking to apply this new Agreement provisionally, in accordance with its constitutional procedures as rapidly as possible, which is recieved by the Secretary-General of the United Nations not later than 25 September 2001, shall be regarded as equal in effect to an instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval. A Government which undertakes to apply this Agreement provisionally, in accordance with its laws and regulations acceptance or approval shall be regarded as a provisional Party thereto until it deposits its instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval or until and including 30 June 2002 whichever is the earlier. The Council may grant an extension of the time within which any Government which is applying this Agreement provisionally may deposit its instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval. (3) If this Agreement has not entered into force definitively or provisionally on 1 October 2001 under the provisions of paragraph (1) or (2) of this Article those Governments which have deposited instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession or made notifications containing an undertaking to apply this Agreement provisionally, in accordance with their laws an regulations, and to seek ratification, acceptance or approval may, by mutual consent, decide that it shall enter into force among themselves. Similarly, if this Agreement has entered into force provisionally but has not entered into force definitively on 31 March 2002, those Governments which have deposited instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession or made the notifications referred to in paragraph (2) of this Article, may, by mutual consent, decide that it shall continue in force provisionally or enter into force definitively among themselves.".</Labeltext>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 October 2001, No. 37769</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>34</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>67</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt; Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2161, p. 308.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>At its eighty-second session held in London from 27 to 28 September 2000, the International Coffee Council approved, by Resolution No. 393, the International Coffee Agreement 2001. The Agreement will be open for signature at United Nations Headquarters, from 1 November 2000 until and including 25 September 2001 by Contracting Parties to the International Coffee Agreement 1994 or the International Coffee Agreement 1994 as extended until 30 September 2001, with modifications, by Resolution 384 of the International Coffee Council on 21 July 1999, and Governments invited to the session of the International Coffee Council at which this Agreement was negotiated, in accordance with its article 43. At its ninety-eighth session, held in London on 28 September 2007, the International Coffee Council decided by Resolution No. 432 to extend the International Coffee Agreement 2001 for a period of one year from 1 October 2007, in accordance with the provisions of paragraph (2) of Article 52. However, as soon as the conditions for its definitive or provisional entry into force are met, the new International Coffee Agreement 2007 shall enter into force, thus terminating the period of extension of the International Coffee Agreement 2001. At its one hundred and first session, held in London on 22 September 2008, the International Coffee Council decided by Resolution No. 438 to further extend the International Coffee Agreement 2001 for one year from 1 October 2008. However, the International Coffee Agreement 2007 shall enter into force as soon as the conditions for its provisional or definitive entry into force are met, thus terminating the period of extension of the International Coffee Agreement 2001.</Text>
          <Text>Further, International Coffee Council took the following decisions:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of decision: Subject:&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text>28 September 2001 Extension until 31 May 2002 of the period for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval, or notifications of provisional application and establishment of special conditions for accession.</Text>
          <Text>21 May 2002 Extension to 25 September 2002 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval, notification of provisional application or accession; </Text>
          <Text>and extension until 31 May 2003 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>26 September 2002 Extension to 31 May 2003 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.</Text>
          <Text>21 May 2003 Extension to 31 May 2004 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.</Text>
          <Text>21 May 2003 Extension to 31 May 2004 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>19 to 21 May 2004 Extension to 31 May 2005 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval or accession.</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 31 May 2005 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>18 to 20 May 2005 Extension to 31 May 2006 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval or accession. </Text>
          <Text>Extension to 31 May 2006 of the time-limit for deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>22 to 25 May 2006 Extension to 31 May 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 31 May 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>Establishment of conditions of accession for Timor-Leste.</Text>
          <Text>24 to 25 May 2007 Extension to 25 September 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 25 September 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval by Belgium/Luxembourg which are applying the Agreement provisionally.</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 25 September 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of an instrument of accession by Timor-Leste.</Text>
          <Text>28 September 2007 Extension of the Agreement for a period of one year, until 30 September 2008, from 1 October 2007; </Text>
          <Text>Extension to 30 September 2008 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession;</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 30 September 2008 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance or approval by States applying the Agreement provisionally; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension to 30 September 2008 of the time-limit for the deposit of an instrument of accession by Timor-Leste.</Text>
          <Text>22 September 2008 Extension of the Agreement for a period of one year, until 30 September 2009, from 1 October 2008.</Text>
          <Text>23 to 25 September 2009 Extension of the Agreement for a period of one year, until 30 September 2010, from 1 October 2009.</Text>
          <Text>21 to 24 September 2010 Extension of the Agreement for a period of one year, until 30 September 2010, from 1 October 2010.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
        <Termination>
          <Label>TERMINATION</Label>
          <Labeltext>* Terminated upon entry into force of the &lt;a href="http://dev.ico.org/documents/ica2007-certified.pdf" target=_blank"&gt;International Coffee Agreement 2007 &lt;/a&gt; (deposited with the &lt;a href="http://www.ico.org/"target=_blank"&gt;International Coffee Organization&lt;/a&gt;).</Labeltext>
        </Termination>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Footer>XIX 43. Commodities</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
