<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>39</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>International Tropical Timber Agreement, 1994</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 26 January 1994</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>provisionally on 1 January 1997, in accordance with article 41(3).</Labeltext>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 January 1997, No. 33484</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>49</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>45</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series, &lt;/i&gt; vol. 1955, p. 81 and depositary notification C.N.89.1995.TREATIES-2 of 22 May 1995 (procès-verbal of rectification of the the Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish authentic texts).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Agreement was adopted on 26 January 1994 at Geneva by the United Nations Conference on Tropical Timber, 1993. It is the successor agreement to the International Tropical Timber Agreement, 1983, which expired on 31 March 1994. It was opened for signature at United Nations Headquarters, from 1 April 1994 until one month after the date of its entry into force, by Governments invited to the United Nations Conference for the Negotiation of a Successor Agreement to the International Tropical Timber Agreement, 1983, in accordance with article 38 (1). Subsequently, the International Tropical Timber Council, at its twenty-second session, held in Bolivia, from 21 to 29 May 1997, by Decision??XXII) dated 23 May 1997, established the conditions for accession to the Agreement and decided that the time limit for the deposit of instruments of accession shall be the duration of the Agreement.</Text>
          <Text>Further, the International Tropical Timber Council took the following decisions:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of decision: Subject:&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>30 May 2000 Extension of the Agreement for a period of three years with effect from 1 January 2001 </Text>
          <Text>i.e, until 31 December 2003.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>4 Nov 2002 Extension of the Agreement for a period of three years with effect from 1 January 2004 </Text>
          <Text>i.e, until 31 December 2006.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>6-11 Nov 2006 Extension of the Agreement until the provisional or definitive entry into force of the </Text>
          <Text>International Tropical Timber Agreement, 2006.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
