<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>41</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Grains Trade Convention, 1995</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>London, 7 December 1994</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 July 1995, in accordance with article 28(2).</Labeltext>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 July 1995, No. 32022</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>15</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>30</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series, &lt;/i&gt; vol. 1882, p. 195.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The International Grains Agreement, 1995, consists of the Grains Trade Convention, 1995, concluded at London on 7 December 1994, and the Food Aid Convention, concluded at London on 5 December 1994 (see hereinafter under chapter IX.41 b). The Grains Trade Convention, was established at a Conference of governments organized by the International Wheat Council on 7 December 1994, while the Food Aid Convention, 1995, was established by the Food Aid Committee at its 69th session on 5 December 1994. Both Conventions, of which the English, French, Russian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, were open for signature at the United Nations Headquarters, New York, from 1 May 1995 until and including 30 June 1995, in accordance with their respective articles 24 and XVII. At its 27th session, held in London on 9 June 2009, the International Grains Council, pursuant to article 2 (1) (e) of the Convention, decided to include rice and its products in the definition of grain or grains, with effect from 1 July 2009. </Text>
          <Text>From its first session, held in London on 6 July 1995, the International Grains Council took the following decisions:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of decision: Subject:&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text>6 July 1995 Extension until 30 June 1996 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States/Organization: </Text>
          <Text>Algeria, Argentina, Barbados, Bolivia, Côte d'Ivoire, Cuba, Ecuador, Egypt, European Community, Iraq, Iran (Islamic Republic of), Israel, Japan, Jordan, Korea (Republic of), Malta, Morocco, Norway, Pakistan, Panama, Russian Federation, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Switzerland, </Text>
          <Text>Tunisia, Turkey, United States of America and Yemen.</Text>
          <Text>17 June 1996 Extension until 30 June 1997 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by thefollowing States: Algeria, Argentina, Bolivia, Côte d'Ivoire, Ecuador, Egypt, Iraq, Jordan, Kazakhstan, Morocco, Norway, Pakistan, Panama, Russian Federation, Saudi Arabia, South Africa, Tunisia, Turkey and United States of America. </Text>
          <Text>(Subsequently, the International Grains Council agreed to grant Malta an extension to 30 June 1997 of the time-limit for the deposit of its instrument of accession.)</Text>
          <Text>3 December 1996 Extension until 30 June 1997 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Yemen.</Text>
          <Text>18 June 1997 Extension until 30 June 1998 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instruments of ratification or accession for Bolivia, Côte d'Ivoire, Ecuador, Egypt, Iraq, Jordan, Kazakhstan, Morocco, Norway, Panama, Russian Federation, Saudi Arabia, United States of America.</Text>
          <Text>15 to 16 June 1998 Extension until 30 June 1999 of the Convention and of the time-limit for the deposit of the instruments of ratification or accession for Bolivia, Côte d'Ivoire, Iraq, Jordan, Kazakhstan, Kenya, Panama, Russian Federation, Saudi Arabia, Ukraine, United States of America and Yemen.</Text>
          <Text>8 June 1999 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2001.</Text>
          <Text>8 December 1999 Extension until 30 June 2000 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession for the Islamic Republic of Iran.</Text>
          <Text>13 to 14 June 2000 Extension until 30 June 2001 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession for Côte d'Ivoire, Iran (Islamic Republic of), Kazakhstan, Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>12 to 13 June 2001 Extension until 30 June 2002 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instruments of ratification or accession for Côte d'Ivoire, Iran (Islamic Republic of), Kazakhstan, Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine; and extension of the Convention until 30 June 2003.</Text>
          <Text>18 to 19 June 2002 Extension until 30 June 2003 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Côte d'Ivoire, Kazakhstan, Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>23 - 24 June 2003 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2005, with effect from 1 July 2003; and Extension until 30 June 2004 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Kazakhstan, Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>14 June 2005 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2007, with effect from 1 July 2005; and Extension until 30 June 2006 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>13 June 2006 Extension until 30 June 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Panama, Russian Federation and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>28 June 2007 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2009, with effect from 1 July 2007.</Text>
          <Text>9 June 2008 Extension until 30 June 2009 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Panama and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>8 June 2009 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2011, with effect from 1 July 2009.</Text>
          <Text>8 June 2009 Extension until 30 June 2010 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Panama and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>7 June 2010 Extension until 30 June 2011 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Panama and Ukraine.</Text>
          <Text>7 December 2010 Extension until 30 June 2011 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Saudi Arabia.</Text>
          <Text>6 June 2011 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2013, with effect from 1 July 2011.</Text>
          <Text>6 June 2011 Extension until 30 June 2012 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Saudi Arabia.</Text>
          <Text>6 December 2013 Extension until 30 June 2014 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Iraq.</Text>
          <Text>9 June 2014 Extension until 30 June 2015 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Iraq.</Text>
          <Text>10 June 2013 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2015, with effect from 1 July 2013.</Text>
          <Text>8 June 2015 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2017, with effect from 1 July 2015. </Text>
          <Text>8 June 2015 Extension until 30 June 2016 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Iraq.</Text>
          <Text>13 June 2016 Extension until 30 June 2017 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Iraq.</Text>
          <Text>5 June 2017 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2019, with effect from 1 July 2017. </Text>
          <Text>5 June 2017 Extension until 30 June 2018 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Iraq.</Text>
          <Text>5 June 2017 Extension until 30 June 2018 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of accession by Oman.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>At its 35th session, held in London on 8 June 2012, the International Grains Council, pursuant to article 2 (1) (e) of the Convention, decided to include copra, cottonseed, palm kernel, groundnuts, rapeseed/canola, soyabeans and sunflowerseed and its products in the definition of grain or grains, with effect from 1 July 2013.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="4">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Provisional application(n)</Entry>
              <Entry colname="4">Ratification, Accession(a), Acceptance(A), Approval(AA)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Algeria</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>20 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Apr 1997 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Argentina</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Jan 1997 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Australia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>28 Jun 1995 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Canada</Entry>
                <Entry>26 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>26 Jun 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Côte d'Ivoire</Entry>
                <Entry>15 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>14 Nov 2002</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cuba</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>16 Oct 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ecuador</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>[ 4 Nov 1997 a]</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Egypt</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>27 May 1998</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>European Union</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Feb 1996 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Holy See</Entry>
                <Entry>20 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>28 Jun 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Hungary</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>29 Jun 1995 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>India</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>27 Jun 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Iran (Islamic Republic of)</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>29 Apr 2002 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Japan</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Dec 1995 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Kazakhstan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Jul 2003 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Kenya</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>15 Jun 1998 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Malta</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>31 Oct 1996 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Mauritius</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>29 Jun 1995 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Morocco</Entry>
                <Entry>26 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>26 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jul 1997</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Norway</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Oct 1997</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Oman</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>20 Dec 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Pakistan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>7 Aug 1996 n</Entry>
                <Entry>3 Apr 1997 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Panama</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Republic of Korea</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>23 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>4 Mar 1996 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Russian Federation</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>3 Dec 2007 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Saudi Arabia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>16 Jan 2012 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>South Africa</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>16 Aug 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>14 Nov 1996 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Switzerland</Entry>
                <Entry>16 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>16 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>16 Apr 1996</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Tunisia</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>31 Jul 1996</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Turkey</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995 n</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Jul 1996 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ukraine</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Oct 2010 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United States of America</Entry>
                <Entry>26 Jun 1995</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 May 1999</Entry>
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations and Reservations</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations and reservations were made upon ratification,</Title>
      <Title>acceptance, approval or accession .)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Argentina</Participant>
        <text type="para">&lt;i&gt;Declaration: &lt;/i&gt;</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic declares that the inclusion of the "Malvinas, South Georgia and South Sandwich Islands" under the incorrect designation of "of Falkland Islands and dependencies" does not in any way affect its rights over those islands and the surrounding waters, which form an integral part of its national territory.</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic likewise rejects the inclusion of the so-called "British Antarctic Territory", while reaffirming its rights to the Argentine Antarctic sector, including sovereignty and the corresponding maritime jurisdiction. It also recalls the safeguards against claims of territorial sovereignty in Antarctica est. ablished by article IV of the Antarctic Treaty of 1 December 1959, to which the Argentine Republic and the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland are parties.</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic does not accept that the provisions of article XV of the Food Aid Convention, 1995, and article 8 of the International Wheat Agreement, 1995, apply to disputes relating to territories under foreign occupation or colonial domination in respect of which there is a sovereignty dispute to resolve for which the United Nations has recommended specific action.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>European Union</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Republic of Austria, the Republic of Finland and the Kingdom of Sweden, having become Member States of the European Community on 1 January 1995, will no longer be individual members of this Convention but will be covered by Community membership thereof. The European Community accordingly also undertakes to exercise the rights and perform the undertakings laid down in this Convention for those three States."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="YES" />
    <EndNotes>
      <Note>
        <index>1</index>
        <text>A Conference of Governments held in London on 6 July 1995 decided to bring the Grains Trade Convention, 1995 into force as of 1 July 1995, among the Governments and International Organisation which had deposited instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, or notifications of provisional application, pursuant to the provisions of article 28 (2) of the Convention.</text>
      </Note>
    </EndNotes>
    <Footer>XIX 41 a. Commodities</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
