<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>30</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol of 1993 extending the International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 1986</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 10 March 1993</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>provisionally on 26 January 1994 and definitively on 25 March 1994, in accordance with article 8(1). The International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 1986 and the Protocol of 1993 extending that Agreement, were consolidated into one single instrument in accordance with the provisions of the Protocol [see chapter XIX.30(b)].</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>26 January 1994, No. 24591</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>7</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>11</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1763, p. 319; Doc. TD/OLIVE OIL.9/6; and depositary notification C.N.343.1995.TREATIES-4 of 10 November 1995 (procès-verbal of rectification of the authentic italian text).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol, of which the Arabic, English, French, Italian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, was adopted at the United Nations Conference on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 1993, held in Geneva on 8, 9 and 10 March 1993. The Protocol was open for signature at United Nations Headquarters, in New York, from 1 May until 31 December 1993 in accordance with its article 5. In accordance with article 1, paragraph 2, so far as the Parties to the Protocol are concerned, the Agreement and the Protocol shall be read and interpreted as one single instrument and shall be known as the "International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 1986, as amended and extended, 1993".</Text>
          <Text>Subsequently, the International Olive Oil Council took the following decisions:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of the decision: Subject:&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>28 January 1994 Extension until 31 March 1994 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance or approval in the case of those Governments which have not </Text>
          <Text>made a notification of provisional application of the Agreement as amended and </Text>
          <Text>extended.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 1994 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance or approval by Governments which have made a notification of </Text>
          <Text>provisional application of the Agreement as amended and extended.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>11 April 1994 Extension until 30 June 1994 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance or approval by signatory Governments.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>31 May 1994 Extension until 31 December 1994 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance, approval of the Protocol and accession by Lebanon to the </Text>
          <Text>Agreement.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>17 November 1994 Extension until 30 June 1995 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance,approval by Algeria, Egypt, Morocco and accession by Lebanon </Text>
          <Text>and the Syrian Arab Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>1 June 1995 Extension until 31 December 1995 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance, approval by Algeria, Egypt, Morocco and accession by Lebanon, </Text>
          <Text>Morocco and the Syrian Arab Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>24 November 1995 Extension until 30 June 1996 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification, acceptance, approval by Morocco and accession by the Syrian Arab </Text>
          <Text>Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>6 June 1996 Extension until 31 December 1996 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco and accession by Croatia and the Syrian Arab Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>20 November 1996 Extension until 30 June 1997 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco and accession by Croatia and the Syrian Arab Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>5 June 1997 Extension until 31 December 1997 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco and accession by Croatia and the Syrian Arab Republic.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>20 November 1997 Extension until 30 June 1998 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>4 June 1998 Extension until 30 December 1998 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>25 November 1998 Extension until 30 June 1999 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco and accession by Croatia and Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>10 June 1999 Extension until 31 December 1999 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco and accession by Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>17 November 1999 Extension until 30 June 2000 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>8 June 2000 Extension until 31 December 2000 of the time-limit for the deposit of the instrument of </Text>
          <Text>ratification by Morocco.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
