<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>49</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 2015</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 9 October 2015</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>provisionally on 1 January 2017, in accordance with article 31(2).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 January 2017, No. 54201</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>13</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>8</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>&lt;a href="https://treaties.un.org/doc/Treaties/2015/10/20151009%2010-35%20AM/Ch_XIX-49.pdf" target = "_ blank"&gt;Certified true copy&lt;/a&gt;</Text>
          <Text>C.N.684.2015.TREATIES-XIX.49 of 23 December 2015 (Opening for signature) and C.N.686.2015.TREATIES-XIX.49 of 23 December 2015 (Issuance of Certified True Copies).</Text>
          <Text>C.N.142.2017.TREATIES-XIX.49 of 22 March 2017 (Proposal of corrections to the French and Spanish authentic texts of the Agreement and to the certified true copies) and C.N.347.2017.TREATIES-XIX.49 of 5 July 2017 (Corrections).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 2015 was adopted on 9 October 2015 at the United Nations Conference for the Negotiation of a Successor Agreement to the International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 2005 held in Geneva from 5 to 9 October 2015. This Agreement shall be open for signature at United Nations Headquarters from 1 January 2016 until and including 31 December 2016 by parties to the International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 2005, and Governments invited to the United Nations Conference for the Negotiation of a Successor Agreement to the International Agreement on Olive Oil and Table Olives, 2005.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="4">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Provisional application(n)</Entry>
              <Entry colname="4">Ratification, Acceptance(A), Approval(AA), Accession(a), Definitive signature(s)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Algeria</Entry>
                <Entry>25 Oct 2016</Entry>
                <Entry>5 Dec 2016 n</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Argentina</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry>28 Sep 2017 n</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>European Union</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Nov 2016</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Dec 2016 n</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Iran (Islamic Republic of)</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Israel</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>22 Nov 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Jordan</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>19 Apr 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lebanon</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>7 Jul 2017 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Libya</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Apr 2017 n</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Montenegro</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Dec 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Jul 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Morocco</Entry>
                <Entry>27 Jul 2016</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Dec 2016 n</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>State of Palestine</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Apr 2017 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Tunisia</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Sep 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>23 Sep 2016</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Turkey</Entry>
                <Entry>14 Sep 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Jun 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Uruguay</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Oct 2016</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>28 Dec 2017</Entry>
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Argentina</Participant>
        <text type="title">Interpretative declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic declares that protection for geographical indications is established in the Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS) Agreement of the World Trade Organization (WTO). This does not imply binding commitments to extend to other products the broad protection that TRIPS provides for wines and spirits.</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic notes that no obligation that it may assume pursuant to the implementation of the Agreement, or subsequently, will prejudice its position on this matter in various multilateral forums, in particular WTO, or in other trade negotiations.</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic also understands that the provisions of article 20 of the 2015 Agreement, regarding geographical indications, should be interpreted in accordance with the standards in the TRIPS Agreement to mean that each member shall provide the legal means to prevent the use of any means in the designation or presentation of a good that indicates or suggests that it originates in a geographical area other than the true place of origin in a manner which misleads the public as to the geographical origin of the good.</text>
        <text type="para">Furthermore, the Argentine Republic interprets that the provisions of article 20 of the 2015 Agreement do not detract from the rights of members of the International Olive Council to protect geographical indications in accordance with their respective legal systems or practices, or prejudice or impair rights already acquired.</text>
        <text type="para">The Argentine Republic declares that the negotiations held pursuant to this Agreement, in order to establish a mechanism for the protection of geographical indications for products covered by the Agreement, should guarantee a commercially fair and balanced outcome that benefits all members ofthe International Olive Council. It undertakes to participate on that basis.</text>
        <text type="para">__________</text>
        <text type="para">Furthermore, the Argentine Republic notified the Secretary-General that, in accordance with article 30 of the Agreement, the Republic of Argentina applies the Agreement provisionally as of 1 January 2017.</text>
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="NO" />
    <EndNotes />
    <Footer>XIX 49. Commodities</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
