<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XIX</Header>
        <Name>COMMODITIES</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>41</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>c</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Food Aid Convention, 1999*</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>London, 13 April 1999</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 July 1999, in accordance with article XXIV(b).</Labeltext>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>1 July 1999, No. 32022</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>14</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>25</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2073, p. 135; et C.N.954.1999.TREATIES-22 of 22 October 1999 (procès-verbal of correction to the original English, French, Russian and Spanish texts of the Convention).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted on 13 April 1999 at London. In accordance with its article XXII (a), the Convention will be open for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York by the Governments and organization referred to in paragraph (e) of article III, from 1 May 1999 until and including 30 June 1999. </Text>
          <Text>In accordance with articles XXII (b) and XXIII (a) of the Convention the Conference of Governments held initially in London on 2 July 1999, and on the following dates thereafter, took the following decisions:</Text>
          <Text>&lt;b&gt;Date of decision Subject&lt;/b&gt;</Text>
          <Text>2 July 1999 Extension until 30 June 2000 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession by the following States/Organisation : </Text>
          <Text>Argentina, Australia, the European Community and the following member States: </Text>
          <Text>Austria, Belgium, Denmark, Finland, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Japan, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Norway, Portugal, Spain, Sweden, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland and the United States of America .</Text>
          <Text>12 to 13 June 2000 Extension until 30 June 2001 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession by the following States/Organisation : </Text>
          <Text>Argentina, the European Community and the following member States: Austria, Belgium, France, Germany, Greece, Italy, Luxembourg, the Netherlands, Portugal, Spain, the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland; Norway and the United States of America.</Text>
          <Text>11 to 12 June 2001 Extension until 30 June 2002 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, Austria, Belgium, France, </Text>
          <Text>Greece, Italy, Luxembourg and Portugal.</Text>
          <Text>17 to 18 June 2002 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2003; and </Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2003 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, Austria, France, Luxembourg and Portugal.</Text>
          <Text>23 - 24 June 2003 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2005, with effect from 1 July 2003; and </Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2004 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, France, Luxembourg and Portugal.</Text>
          <Text>14 June 2004 Extension until 30 June 2005 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Luxembourg, Malta, Poland, Portugal, Slovakia and Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text>13 June 2005 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2007 with effect from 1 July 2005; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2006 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Poland, Portugal, Slovakia and Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text>15 June 2006 Extension until 30 June 2007 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of ratification or accession by the following States: Argentina, Cyprus, Czech Republic, </Text>
          <Text>Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Poland, Portugal, Slovakia and Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text>28 June 2007 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2008, with effect from 1 July 2007.</Text>
          <Text>1 June 2007 Extension until 30 June 2008 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of accession by the following States: Argentina, Bulgaria, Cyprus,Czech Republic, Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Romania, Slovak Republic, and Slovenia.</Text>
          <Text>6 June 2008 Extension of the Convention until 30June 2009 with effect from 1 July 2008; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2009 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of accession by the following States: Argentina, Bulgaria, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Romania and Slovak Republic.</Text>
          <Text>5 June 2009 Extension of the Convention until 30June 2010 with effect from 1 July 2009; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2010 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of accession by the following States: Argentina, Bulgaria, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Romania and Slovak Republic.</Text>
          <Text>4 June 2010 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2011 with effect from 1 July 2010; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2011 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of accession by the following States: Bulgaria, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Romania and Slovak Republic.</Text>
          <Text>18 May 2011 Extension of the Convention until 30 June 2012 with effect from 1 July 2011; and</Text>
          <Text>Extension until 30 June 2012 of the time-limit for the deposit of instruments of accession by the following States: Argentina, Bulgaria, Cyprus, Czech Republic, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Malta, Romania and Slovak Republic.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
        <Termination>
          <Label>TERMINATION</Label>
          <Labeltext>At the 106th Session of the Food Aid Committee held on 11 June 2012, all the parties agreed that the Food Aid Convention, 1999 (FAC) would expire on 30 June 2012 and that on the expiration of the FAC, the Convention would be deemed to be terminated and would cease to be in force.</Labeltext>
        </Termination>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Footer>XIX 41 c. Commodities</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
