<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XVIII</Header>
        <Name>PENAL MATTERS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>11</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>International Convention for the Suppression of the Financing of Terrorism</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>New York, 9 December 1999</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>10 April 2002, in accordance with article 26 which reads as follows: "1. This Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day following the date of the deposit of the twenty-second instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession with the Secretary-General of the United Nations. 2. For each State ratifying, accepting, approving or acceding to the Convention after the deposit of the twenty-second instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, the Convention shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after deposit by such State of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>10 April 2002, No. 38349</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>132</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>188</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2178, p. 197; Resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_54_109-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/54/109&lt;/a&gt;; depositary notifications C.N.327.2000.TREATIES-12 of 30 May 2000 (rectification of the original text of the Convention); and C.N.3.2002.TREATIES-1 of 2 January 2002 [proposal for corrections to the original text of the Convention (Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish authentic texts)] and C.N.86.2002.TREATIES-4 of 1 February 2002 [Rectification of the original of the Convention (Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish authentic texts)]; C.N.312.2002.TREATIES-14 of 4 April 2002 [proposal of a correction to the original of the Convention (Spanish authentic text)] and C.N.420.2002.TREATIES-20 of 3 May 2002 [rectification of the original of the Convention (Spanish authentic text)].</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted by Resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_54_109-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;54/109&lt;/a&gt; of 9 December 1999 at the fourth session of the General Assembly of the United Nations. In accordance with its article 25 (1), the Convention will be open for signature by all States at United Nations Headquarters from 10 January 2000 to 31 December 2001.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
