<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XVIII</Header>
        <Name>PENAL MATTERS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>12</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol to Prevent, Suppress and Punish Trafficking in Persons, Especially Women and Children, supplementing the United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>New York, 15 November 2000</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>25 December 2003, in accordance with article 17which reads as follows: "1. This Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the fortieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, except that it shall not enter into force before the entry into force of the Convention. For the purpose of this paragraph, any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of such organization. 2. For each State or regional economic integration organization ratifying, accepting, approving or acceding to this Protocol after the deposit of the fortieth instrument of such action, this Protocol shall enter into force on the thirtieth day after the date of deposit by such State or organization of the relevant instrument or on the date this Protocol enters into force pursuant to paragraph 1 of this article, whichever is the later.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>25 December 2003, No. 39574</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>117</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>173</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2237, p. 319; &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_55_383-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Doc. A/55/383&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol was adopted by resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_55_25-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/55/25&lt;/a&gt; of 15 November 2000 at the fifty-fifth session of the General Assembly of the United Nations. In accordance with its article 16, the Protocol will be open for signature by all States and by regional economic integration organizations, provided that at least one Member State of such organization has signed the Protocol, from 12 to 15 December 2000 at the Palazzi di Giustizia in Palermo, Italy, and thereafter at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 12 December 2002.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
