<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg3</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXI</Header>
        <Name>LAW OF THE SEA</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>6</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Montego Bay, 10 December 1982</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 November 1994, in accordance with article 308(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 November 1994, No. 31363</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>157</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>168</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1833, p. 3; depositary notifications C.N.236.1984.TREATIES-7 of 5 October 1984 (procès-verbal of rectification of the English and Spanish authentic texts); C.N.202.1985.TREATIES-17 of 23 August 1985 (procès-verbal of rectification of the original English text); C.N.17.1986.TREATIES-1 of 7 April 1986 (procès-verbal of rectification of the original Arabic, Chinese, English, French and Spanish texts of the Final Act); C.N.166.1993.TREATIES-4 of 9 August 1993 (procès-verbal of rectification of the original Arabic, Chinese, English, French and Spanish texts of the Final Act); and vol.?904, p.?20 (procès-verbal of rectification of the original French text); C.N.694.2005.TREATIES-5 of 7September 2005 (Proposal of correction to Article 5 of Annex II of the authentic Spanish text of the Convention) and C.N.1023.2005.TREATIES-7 of 7 October 2005 [procès-verbal of rectification of the original of the Convention (Spanish authentic text)].</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted by the Third United Nations Conference on the Law of the Sea and opened for signature, together with the Final Act of the Conference, at Montego Bay, Jamaica, on 10 December 1982. The Conference was convened pursuant to resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_28_3067-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;3067 (XXVIII)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt; adopted by the General Assembly on 16 November 1973. The Conference held eleven sessions, from 1973 to 1982, as follows:</Text>
          <Text>- First session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 3 to 15 December 1973;</Text>
          <Text>- Second session: Parque Central, Caracas, 20 June to 29 August 1974;</Text>
          <Text>- Third session: United Nations Office at Geneva, 17 March to 9 May 1975;</Text>
          <Text>- Fourth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 15 March to 7 May 1976;</Text>
          <Text>- Fifth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 2 August to 17 September 1976;</Text>
          <Text>- Sixth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 23 May to 15 July 1977;</Text>
          <Text>- Seventh session: United Nations Office at Geneva, 28 March to 19 May 1978;</Text>
          <Text>- Resumed seventh session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 21 August to 15 September 1978;</Text>
          <Text>- Eighth session: United Nations Office at Geneva, 19 March to 27 April 1979;</Text>
          <Text>- Resumed eighth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 19 July to 24 August 1979;</Text>
          <Text>- Ninth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 3 March to 4 April 1980;</Text>
          <Text>- Resumed ninth session: United Nations Office at Geneva, 28 July to 29 August 1980;</Text>
          <Text>- Tenth session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 9 March to 24 April 1981;</Text>
          <Text>- Resumed tenth session: United Nations Office at Geneva, 3 to 28 August 1981;</Text>
          <Text>- Eleventh session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 8 March to 30 April 1982;</Text>
          <Text>- Resumed eleventh session: United Nations Headquarters, New York, 22 to24 September 1982;</Text>
          <Text>- Final Part of the eleventh session: Montego Bay, Jamaica, 6 to 10 December 1982.</Text>
          <Text>The Conference also adopted a Final Act&lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt; with, annexed thereto, nine resolutions and a statement of understanding. The text of the Final Act has been reproduced as document &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_CONF.62_121-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/CONF.62/121 and Corr. 1 to 8.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
