<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXV</Header>
        <Name>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>4</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Tampere Convention on the Provision of Telecommunication Resources for Disaster Mitigation and Relief Operations</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Tampere, 18 June 1998</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>8 January 2005, in accordance with article 12which reads as follows: "1. This Convention shall be open for signature by all States which are members of the United Nations or of the International Telecommunication Union at the Intergovernmental Conference on Emergency Telecommunications in Tampere on 18 June 1998, and thereafter at the headquarters of the United Nations, New York, from 22 June 1998 to 21 June 2003. 2. A State may express its consent to be bound by this Convention: a) by signature (definitive signature); b) by signature subject to ratification, acceptance or approval followed by deposit of an instrument of ratification, acceptance or approval; or c) by deposit of an instrument of accession. 3. The Convention shall enter into force thirty (30) days after the deposit of instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession or definitive signature of thirty (30) States. 4. For each State which signs definitively or deposits an instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, after the requirement set out in paragraph 3 of this Article has been fulfilled, this Convention shall enter into force thirty (30) days after the date of the definitive signature or consent to be bound.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>8 January 2005, No. 40906</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>60</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>48</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2296, p. 5; Depositary notifications C.N.608.1998.TREATIES-8 of 4 December 1998; and C.N.782.1999.TREATIES-13 of 28 September 1999 (rectification of the Convention and transmission of relevant procès-verbal).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was opened for signature at Tampere by all States Members of the United Nations or of the International Telecommunication Union on 18 June 1998, and thereafter at the United Nations Headquarters in New York from 22 June 1998 where it will remain open until 21 June 2003, in accordance with its article 12.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
