<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXV</Header>
        <Name>TELECOMMUNICATIONS</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>3</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Agreement establishing the Asia-Pacific Institute for Broadcasting Development</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kuala Lumpur, 12 August 1977</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>6 March 1981, in accordance with article 16.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>6 March 1981, No. 19609</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>14</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>26</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1216, p. 81&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;; depositary notifications C.N.130.1986.TREATIES-1 of 13 June 1986 (amended authentic text in Chinese, English, French and Russian) and C.N.195.1986.TREATIES-3 of 15 October 1986 (Adoption of the amended text of the Agreement)&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;; and C.N.707.1999.TREATIES-1 of 6 August 1999 [amendments &lt;i&gt;(see chapter XXV.3 a) &lt;/i&gt;].</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Agreement was adopted on 12 August 1977 by the Intergovernmental Meeting on the Asia-Pacific Institute for Broadcasting Development convened by the United Nations Development Programme at Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, from 10 to 12 August 1977.</Text>
          <Text>According to paragraph 3 of its article 14, the Agreement was to remain open for signature at the UNESCO Headquarters in Paris until 31 March 1978 and would then be transmitted for deposit to the Secretary-General of the United Nations. Instead, signatures on behalf of 11 States were affixed individually during the period 12 September 1977 - 11 October 1978 on separate copies of the text of the Agreement established by the Asia-Pacific Institute for Broadcasting Development which were transmitted to the Secretary-General in June 1979. By depositary notification of 3 August 1979, the Secretary-General, in his capacity as the designated depositary, submitted for approval by all States having participated in the adoption of the Agreement or having signed the separate copies, the original text of the Agreement, similar to the text adopted at Kuala Lumpur on 12 August 1977 except for minor changes in the formal clauses as were warranted by the circumstances. No objection having been received from the States concerned within ninety days from the notification, the original of the Agreement was deposited with the Secretary-General on 2 November 1979.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
