<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>3</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>b</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Basel Protocol on Liability and Compensation for Damage Resulting from Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Basel, 10 December 1999</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>see article 29 which reads as follows: "1. The Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the twentieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, formal confirmation, approval or accession. 2. For each State or regional economic integration organization which ratifies, accepts, approves or formally confirms the Protocol or accedes thereto after the date of the deposit of the twentieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval, formal confirmation or accession, it shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit by such State or regional economic integration organization of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval, formal confirmation or accession. 3. For the purpose of paragraphs 1 and 2 of this Article, any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of such organization".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>13</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>11</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Doc.&lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/UNEP_CHW.1_WG.1_9_2-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;UNEP/CHW.1/WG/1/9/2&lt;/a&gt;; depositary notification C.N.120.2005.TREATIES-12 of 23 February 2005 [Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (authentic Spanish text)] and C.N.407.2005.TREATIES-3 of 25 May 2005 [(Corrections to the original of the Protocol (Authentic Spanish text)].</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol will be open for signature by States and by regional economic integration organizations Parties to the Basel Convention in Berne at the Federal Department of Foreign Affairs of Switzerland from 6 to 17 March 2000 and at United Nations Headquarters in New York from 1 April 2000 to 10 December 2000, in accordance with its article 26.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
