<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>7</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Kyoto Protocol to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kyoto, 11 December 1997</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 February 2005, in accordance with article 25(1) and article 25 (3) which read as follows:  "1. This Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date on which not less than 55 Parties to the Convention, incorporating Parties included in Annex I which accounted in total for at least 55 per cent of the total carbon dioxide emissions for 1990 of the Parties included in Annex I, have deposited their instruments of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession." "3. For each State or regional economic integration organization that ratifies, accepts or approves this Protocol or accedes thereto after the conditions set out in paragraph 1 above for entry into force have been fulfilled, this Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day following the date of deposit of its instrument of ratification acceptance, approval or accession".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 February 2005, No. 30822</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>83</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>192</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt; , vol. 2303, p. 162; depositary notifications C.N.101.2004.TREATIES-1 of 11 February 2004 [Proposed corrections to the original texts of the Protocol (Arabic and French versions)] and C.N.439.2004.TREATIES-4 of 12 May 2004 [Corrections to the original texts of the Protocol (Arabic and French versions)]; C.N.380.2007.TREATIES-5 of 17 April 2007 (Adoption of an amendment to Annex B of the Protocol).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol was adopted at the third session of the Conference of the Parties to the 1992 United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change (the Convention), held at Kyoto (Japan) from 1 to 11 December 1997. The Protocol shall be open for signature by States and regional economic integration organizations which are Parties to the Convention at United Nations Headquarters in New York from 16 March 1998 to 15 March 1999 in accordance with its article 24 (1).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
