<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>3</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Basel, 22 March 1989</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>5 May 1992, in accordance with article 25(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>5 May 1992, No. 28911</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>53</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>186</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1673, p. 57; and depositary notifications C.N.302.1992.TREATIES-9 of 25 November 1992 (procès-verbal of rectification of the original English text)&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt; ; C.N.248.1993.TREATIES-7 of 7 September 1993 (procès-verbal of rectification of the authentic French text); C.N.144.1994.TREATIES-4 of 27 June 1994 (procès-verbal of rectification of the authentic Arabic, Chinese, English and Spanish texts); C.N.15.1997.TREATIES-1 of 20 Februrary 1997 (procès-verbal of rectification of the authentic Russian text); C.N.77.1998. TREATIES-2 of 6 May 1998 (amendment to annex I and adoption of annexes VIII and IX)&lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt; ; C.N.245.2003.TREATIES-4 of 27 March 2003 [proposal of corrections to the original text of the Convention (authentic Chinese text)] and C.N.321.2003.TREATIES-5 of 29 April 2003 [Corrections to the original of the Convention (authentic Chinese text)]; C.N.399.2003.TREATIES-9 of 20 May 2003 (Proposal of amendments to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention) and C.N.1314.2003.TREATIES-12 of 20 November 2003 (Entry into force of amendments to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention); C.N.119.2005.TREATIES-2 of 23 February 2005 [(Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Convention (authentic Spanish text)] and C.N.406.2005.TREATIES-6 of 25 May 2005 [(Corrections to the original of the Convention (Authentic Spanish text)]; C.N.263.2005.TREATIES-4 of 8 April 2005 (Proposal of amendments to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention) and C.N.263.2005.TREATIES-4 of (Re-issued) of 13 June 2005 (Proposal of amendments to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention) and C.N.1044.2005.TREATIES-7 of 10 October 2005 (Entry into force of amendments to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention); C.N.1038.2007.TREATIES-5 of 14 November 2007 (Proposal of corrections to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention) and C.N.119.2008.TREATIES-1 of 26 February 2008 (Corrections to Annexes VIII and IX); C.N.125.2008.TREATIES-2 of 26 February 2008 (Proposal of Correction to Annex IX of the Convention) and C.N.243.2008.TREATIES-3 of 7 April 2008 (Correction to Annex IX of the Convention); C.N.397.2008.TREATIES-4 of 27 May 2008 (Proposal of Correction to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention) and C.N.609.2008.TREATIES-8 of 28 August 2008 (Corrections to Annexes VIII and IX of the Convention); C.N.644.2008.TREATIES-9 of 18 September 2008 (Proposal of correction to Annex IX of the Convention) and C.N.778.2008.TREATIES-10 of 28 October 2008 (Corrections to Annex IX of the Convention); C.N.284.2011.TREATIES-2 of 18 May 2011 (Proposal of correction to the original text of [the] Convention (French version) and to the certified true copies) and C.N.359.2011.TREATIES-3 of 20 June 2011 (Correction to the original text of Convention (French version) and to the certified true copies); C.N.760.2011.TREATIES-6 of 28 November 2011 (Proposal of correction to Annex VIII of the Convention) and C.N.824.2011.TREATIES-7 of 30 December 2011 (Correction to Annex VIII of the Convention); C.N.965.2013.TREATIES-XXVII-3 of 26 November 2013 (Amendments to Annex IX) and C.N.304.2014.TREATIES-XXVII-3 of 28 May 2014 (Entry into force of the Amendments to Annex IX).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention, of which the Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, was adopted on 22 March 1989 by the Conference of Plenipotentiaries which was convened at Basel from 20 to 22 March 1989. In accordance with its article 21, the Convention, which was open for signature at the Federal Department of Foreign Affairs of Switzerland in Berne from 23 March 1989 to 30 June 1989, was open thereafter at the Headquarters of the United Nations in New York until 22 March 1990, by all States, Namibia, and by political and/or economic integration organizations&lt;superscript&gt;4&lt;/superscript&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
