<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>17</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Minamata Convention on Mercury</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kumamoto, 10 October 2013</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 August 2017, in accordance with article 31(1), the Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the fiftieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession. For each State or regional economic integration organization that ratifies, accepts or approves this Convention or accedes thereto after the deposit of the fiftieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, the Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit by such State or regional economic integration organization of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession. Any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of that organization.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>16 August 2017, No. 54669</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>128</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>85</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>&lt;a href="http://treaties.un.org/doc/Treaties/2013/10/20131010%2011-16%20AM/CTC-XXVII-17.pdf" target = "_ blank"&gt;Certified true copy&lt;/a&gt;</Text>
          <Text>C.N.560.2014.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 19 September 2014 (proposal of corrections to the original text of the Convention (Arabic, Chinese and Spanish versions) and to the certified true copies) and C.N.827.2014.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 26 December 2014 (Corrections); C.N.821.2014.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 9 January 2015 (Proposal of correction to the orginal text of the Convention (Spanish version) and to the certified true copies) and C.N.244.2015.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 9 April 2015 (Correction); C.N.959.2016.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 19 January 2017 (Proposal of corrections to the orginal text of the Convention (Chinese version) and to the certified true copies) and C.N.253.2017.TREATIES-XXVII.17 of 27 April 2017 (Corrections).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted on 10 October 2013 at Kumamoto (Japan) on the occasion of the Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Minamata Convention on Mercury held from 7 to 11 October 2013.</Text>
          <Text>The Convention was opened for signature by States and regional economic integration organizations at Kumamoto, Japan, on 10 and 11 October 2013, and, thereafter, at the United Nations Headquarters in New York until 9 October 2014.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
