<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>4</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>b</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol on Strategic Environmental Assessment to the Convention on Environmental Impact Assessment in a Transboundary Context</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kiev, 21 May 2003</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>11 July 2010, in accordance with article 24(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>11 July 2010, No. 34028</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>38</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>32</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2685, p. 140; Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/mp.eia.2003.2.e.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;ECE/MP.EIA/2003/2&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
          <Text>C.N.951.2016.TREATIES-XXVII.4.b of 16 January 2017 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (English, French and Russian texts) and to the certified true copies) and C.N.244.2017.TREATIES-XXVII.4.b of 21 April 2017 (Corrections).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The above Protocol was adopted on 21 May 2003 by the Extraordinary Meeting of the Parties to the Convention of 25 February 1991 on Environmental Impact Assessment in a Transboundary Context held in Kiev, from 21 to 23 May 2003. The Protocol was opened for signature from 21 to 23 May 2003 in Kiev, and will remain open for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 31 December 2003 by States members of the Economic Commission for Europe as well as States having consultative status with the Economic Commission for Europe, pursuant to paragraphs 8 and 11 of Economic and Social Council resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/E_RES_36_IV-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;36 (IV)&lt;/a&gt; of 28 March 1947, and by regional economic integration organizations constituted by sovereign States members of the Economic Commission for Europe to which their member States have transferred competence over matters governed by the Protocol, including the competence to enter into treaties in respect of these matters.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
