<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>1</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>g</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol to the 1979 Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution on Persistent Organic Pollutants</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Aarhus, 24 June 1998</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>23 October 2003, in accordance with article 18(1)which reads as follows: "1. The present Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day following the date on which the sixteenth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession has been deposited with the Depositary. 2. For each State and organization referred to in article 15, paragraph 1, which ratifies, accepts or approves the present Protocol or accedes thereto after the deposit of the sixteenth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, the Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day following the date of deposit by such Party of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>23 October 2003, No. 21623</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>36</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>33</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2230, p. 79; Document of the Economic and Social Council &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/EB.AIR_WG.1_1998_2-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;EB.AIR/1998/2&lt;/a&gt;; C.N.554.2010.TREATIES-2 of 14 September 2010 (Amendments to Annexes V and VII) and C.N.844.2010.TREATIES-8 of 20 December 2010 (Entry into force of the Amendments to Annexes V and VII to the Protocol)&lt;superscript&gt;1,2&lt;/superscript&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>(1) Open for signature at Aarhus (Denmark) from 24 to 25 June 1998, then at United Nations Headquarters until 21 December 1998, by States members of the Economic Commission for Europe as well as States having consultative status with the Commission pursuant to paragraph 8 of Economic and Social Council resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/E_RES_36_IV-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;36 (IV)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt; of 28 March 1947, and by regional economic integration organizations, constituted by sovereign States members of the Commission, which have competence in respect of the negotiation, conclusion and application of international agreements in matters covered by the Protocol, provided that the States and organizations concerned are Parties to the Convention.</Text>
          <Text></Text>
          <Text>(2) By Decision 2009/3, adopted on 18 December 2009 at the twenty-seventh session of the Executive Body, held in Geneva, Switzerland from 14 to 18 December 2009, the Parties adopted Amendments to Annexes V and VII to the Protocol, in accordance with paragraph 4 of article 14 of the Protocol. </Text>
          <Text>In accordance with paragraphs 4 and 5, of article 14, Amendments to annexes V and VII shall be adopted by consensus of the Parties present at a session of the Executive Body. On the expiry of ninety days from the date of its communication to all Parties by the Executive Secretary of the Commission, an amendment to any such annex shall become effective for those Parties which have not submitted to the Depositary a notification in accordance with the provisions of paragraph 5 below, provided that at least sixteen Parties have not submitted such a notification.</Text>
          <Text>5. Any Party that is unable to approve an amendment to annex V or VII shall so notify the Depositary in writing within ninety days from the date of the communication of its adoption. The Depositary shall without delay notify all Parties of any suchnotification received. A Party may at any time substitute an acceptance for its previous notification and, upon deposit of an instrument of acceptance with the Depositary, the amendment to such an annex shall become effective for that Party (See depositary notification C.N.554.2010.TREATIES-2, of 14 September 2010).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
