<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>3</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>a</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Amendment to the Basel Convention on the Control of Transboundary Movements of Hazardous Wastes and their Disposal</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 22 September 1995</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>see article 17 (5) of the Convention which reads as follows: "Instruments of ratification, approval, formal confirmation or acceptance of amendments shall be deposited with the Depositary. Amendments adopted in accordance with paragraphs 3 or 4 [of article 17 of the Convention] shall enter into force between Parties having accepted them on the ninetieth day after the receipt by the Depositary of their instrument of ratification, approval, formal confirmation or acceptance by at least three-fourths of the Parties who accepted them or by at least two thirds of the Parties to the protocol concerned who accepted them, except as may otherwise be provided in such protocol. The amendments shall enter into force for any other Party on the ninetieth day after that Party deposits its instrument of ratification, approval, formal confirmation or acceptance of the amendments.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>93</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>&lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/UNEP_CHW.3_35-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Doc. UNEP/CHW.3/35&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>By decision III/1, of 22 September 1995, the Third meeting of the Conference of the Contracting Parties to the above Convention, which took place in Geneva from 18 to 22 September 1995, adopted an Amendment to the Convention (including the adoption of Annex VII).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
