<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>16</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Protocol on Civil Liability and Compensation for Damage Caused by the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents on Transboundary Waters to the 1992 Convention on the Protection and Use of Transboundary Watercourses and International Lakes and to the 1992 Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Kiev, 21 May 2003</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>see article 29 which reads as follows: "1. The Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the sixteenth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession. 2. Article 2, paragraph 2(e)(iii), shall take effect when thresholds, limits of liability and minimum limits of financial securities for pipelines are set in annexes I and II in accordance with article 24, paragraphs 8 and 9. 3. For the purposes of paragraph 1, any instrument deposited by an organization referred to in article 27 shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by States members of such an organization. 4. For each State or organization referred to in article 27 which ratifies, accepts or approves the Protocol or accedes thereto after the deposit of the sixteenth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, the Protocol shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit by such State or organization of its instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>24</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>1</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/ECE_MP.WAT_11-ECE_CP.TEIA_9-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Doc. ECE/MP.WAT/11-ECE/CP.TEIA/9&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The above Protocol was adopted on 21 May 2003 by the Extraordinary Meeting of the Parties to the Convention of 17 March 1992 on the Protection and Use of Transboundary Watercourses and International Lakes and the Convention of 17 March 1992 on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents held in Kiev from 21 to 23 May 2003. The Protocol was opened for signature from 21 to 23 May 2003 in Kiev, and will remain open for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 31 December 2003 by States members of the Economic Commission for Europe as well as States having consultative status with the Economic Commission for Europe, pursuant to paragraph 8 of Economic and Social Council resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/E_RES_36_IV-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;36 (IV)&lt;/a&gt; of 28 March 1947, and by regional economic integration organizations constituted by sovereign States members of the Economic Commission for Europe to which their member States have transferred competence in respect of matters governed by the Protocol, including the competence to enter into treaties in respect of these matters.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="3">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Ratification, Acceptance(A), Approval(AA), Accession(a)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Armenia</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Austria</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Dec 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belgium</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Bosnia and Herzegovina</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Bulgaria</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cyprus</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Denmark</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Estonia</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Finland</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Georgia</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Greece</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Hungary</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry>25 Jun 2004</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Latvia</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lithuania</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Luxembourg</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Monaco</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Norway</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Poland</Entry>
                <Entry>13 Jun 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Portugal</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Republic of Moldova</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Romania</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sweden</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ukraine</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 2003</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations were made upon ratification,</Title>
      <Title>acceptance, approval or accession.)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Belgium</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">This signature engages also the Waloon region, the Flemish region, and the Brussels-Capital region.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Denmark</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">Both the Faroe Islands and Greeland are self-governing under Home Rule Acts, which implies &lt;i&gt;inter alia &lt;/i&gt; that environmental affairs in general and the areas covered by the Protocol are governed by the right of self-determination.</text>
        <text type="para">Signing by Denmark of the Protocol, therefore does not necessarily mean that Danish ratification will in due course include the Faroe Islands and Greenland.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="YES" />
    <EndNotes>
      <Note>
        <index>1</index>
        <text>For the purpose of entry into force of the [Convention/Protocol] , any instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of that Organization.</text>
      </Note>
    </EndNotes>
    <Footer>XXVII 16. Environment</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
