<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>8</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>b</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Nagoya Protocol on Access to Genetic Resources and the Fair and Equitable Sharing of Benefits Arising from their Utilization to the Convention on Biological Diversity</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Nagoya, 29 October 2010</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>12 October 2014, in accordance with article 33.</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>12 October 2014, No. 30619</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>92</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>104</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Doc.: &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/UNEP_CBD_COP_DEC_X_1-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;UNEP/CBD/COP/DEC/X/1&lt;/a&gt; of 29 October 2010</Text>
          <Text>C.N.115.2011.TREATIES-7 of 18 March 2011 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (French Version) and to the Certified true copies) and C.N.356.2011.TREATIES-26 of 17 June 2011(Corrections to the original text of the Protocol (French version) and to the certified true copies); C.N.711.2011.TREATIES-70 of 1 November 2011 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (French Version) and to the Certified true copies) and C.N.53.2012.TREATIES-88 of 31 January 2012 (Corrections to the original text of the Protocol (French version) and to the Certified true copies); C.N.825.2011.TREATIES-78 of 18 January 2012 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (Chinese Version) and to the Certified true copies) and C.N.200.2012.TREATIES-XXVII.8.b of 18 April 2012 (Corrections to the original text of the Protocol (Chinese version) and to the Certified true copies); C.N.429.2016.TREATIES-XXVII.8.b of 16 June 2016 (Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Protocol (Chinese Version) and to the Certified true copies) and C.N.625.2016.TREATIES-XXVII.8.b of 15 September 2016 (Corrections to the original text of the Protocol (Chinese version) and to the Certified true copies).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The above Protocol was adopted on 29 October 2010 at Nagoya, Japan, during the tenth meeting of the Parties to the Convention on Biological Diversity. In accordance with its article 32, the Protocol will be opened for signature by Parties to the Convention at the United Nations Headquarters in New York from 2 February 2011 until 1 February 2012.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
