<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>4</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>c</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Amendment to the Convention on Environmental Impact Assessment in a Transboundary Context</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Cavtat, 4 June 2004</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>23 October 2017, in accordance with article 14(4) of the Convention which reads as follows: "Amendments to the above Convention adopted in accordance with paragraph 3 of this Article shall be submitted by the Depositary to all Parties for ratification, approval or acceptance. They shall enter into force for Parties having ratified, approved or accepted them on the ninetieth day after the receipt by the Depositary of notification of their ratification, approval or acceptance by at least three fourths of these Parties. Thereafter they shall enter into force for any other Party on the ninetieth day after that Party deposits its instrument of ratification, approval or acceptance of the amendments".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>23 October 2017, No. 34028</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>31</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>Depositary Notification C.N.1143.2004.TREATIES-1 of 8 November 2004 (Adoption of Amendment). C.N.953.2016.TREATIES-XXVII.4.c of 16 January 2017 (Proposal of corrections to the Amendment) and C.N.245.2017.TREATIES-XXVII.4.c of 21 April 2017 (Corrections).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>At the third meeting of the Parties to the above Convention, held in Cavtat, Croatia, from 1 to 4 June 2004, the Parties adopted, in accordance with the procedure laid down in article 14 (3) of the Convention on Environmental Impact Assessment in a Transboundary Context, the second Amendment to the said Convention as set out in Annex VII to the report of the Third Meeting of the Parties (Decision III/7).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
