<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVI</Header>
        <Name>DISARMAMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>2</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Convention on Prohibitions or Restrictions on the Use of Certain Conventional Weapons which may be deemed to be Excessively Injurious or to have Indiscriminate Effects (with Protocols I, II and III)</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 10 October 1980</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>2 December 1983 in accordance with article 5 (1) and (3).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>2 December 1983, No. 22495</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>50</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>125</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 1342, p. 137; depositary notifications C.N.356.1981. TREATIES-7 of 14 January 1982 (procès-verbal of rectification of the Chinese authentic text) and C.N.320.1982. TREATIES-11 of 21 January 1983 (procès-verbal of rectification of the Final Act).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention and its annexed Protocols were adopted by the United Nations Conference on Prohibitions or Restrictions of the Use of Certain Conventional Weapons Which May Be Deemed Excessively Injurious or to Have Indiscriminate Effects, held in Geneva from 10 to 28 September 1979 and from 15 September to 10 October 1980. The Conference was convened pursuant to General Assembly resolutions &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_32_152-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;32/152&lt;/a&gt; of 19 December 1977 and &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_33_70-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;33/70&lt;/a&gt; of 14 December 1978. The original of the Convention with the annexed Protocols, of which the Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish texts are equally authentic, is deposited with the Secretary-General of the United Nations. The Convention was open for signature by all States at United Nations Headquarters in New York for a period of twelve months from 10 April 1981.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
