<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>1</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>e</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol to the 1979 Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution on Further Reduction of Sulphur Emissions</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Oslo, 14 June 1994</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>5 August 1998, in accordance with article 15(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>5 August 1998, No. 21623</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>28</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>29</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2030, p. 122; Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/EB.AIR_R.84-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;EB.AIR/R.84&lt;/a&gt;; E/ECE/ENHS/001/2002/l (Adoption of adjustments).&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol, adopted on 13 June 1994 by the Executive Body for the Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution at its special session held in Oslo on 13 and 14 June 1994, was open for signature at Oslo until 14 June 1994, and thereafter, at United Nations Headquarters, New York, until 12 December 1994, in accordance with its article 12 (1). The Protocol is open to signature by States members of the Economic commission for Europe as well as States having consultative status with the Comission, pursuant to paragraph 8 of &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/NR075250.pdf"&gt;Economic and social Council Resolution 36 (IV)&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt; of 28 March 1947&lt;/a&gt;, and by regional economic integration organizations, constituted by sovereign Sates members of the Commission, which have competence in respect of the negotiation, conclusion and application of international agreements in matters covered by the Protocol, provided that the States and organizations concerned are Parties to the 1979 Convention.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
