<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVI</Header>
        <Name>DISARMAMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>4</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>New York, 10 September 1996</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>[see article XIV]. This Treaty will enter into force 180 days after the date of deposit of the instruments of ratification by all States listed in Annex 2 to this Treaty (that is to say: Algeria, Argentina, Australia, Austria, Bangladesh, Belgium, Brazil, Bulgaria, Canada, Chile, China, Colombia, Democratic People's Republic of Korea, Egypt, Finland, France, Germany, Hungary, India, Indonesia, Iran (Islamic Republic of), Israel, Italy, Japan, Mexico, Netherlands, Norway, Pakistan, Peru, Poland, Republic of Korea, Romania, Russian Federation, Slovakia, South Africa, Spain, Sweden, Switzerland, Turkey, Ukraine, United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, United States of America, Viet Nam and Zaire), but in no case earlier than two years after its opening for signature. 2. If this Treaty has not entered into force three years after the date of the anniversary of its opening for signature, the Depositary shall convene a Conference of the States that have already deposited their instruments of ratification upon the request of a majority of those States. That Conference shall examine the extent to which the requirement set out in paragraph 1 has been met and shall consider and decide by consensus what measure consistent with international law may facilitate the early entry into force of this Treaty. 3. Unless otherwise decided by the Conference referred to in paragraph 2 or other such conferences, this process shall be repeated at subsequent anniversaries of the opening for signature of this Treaty, until its entry into force. 4. All States Signatories shall be invited to attend the Conference referred to in paragraph 2 and any subsequent conferences as referred to in paragraph 3, as observers. 5. For States whose instruments of ratification or accession are deposited subsequent to the entry into force of this Treaty, it shall enter into force on the 30th day following the date of deposit of their instruments of ratification or accession.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>183</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>166</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>&lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_50_1027-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Doc. A/50/1027&lt;/a&gt;; and C.N.429.2002.TREATIES-3 of 6 May 2002 [proposed corrections to the original text of the treaty (Arabic text)] and C.N.629.2002.TREATIES-4 of 11 June 2002 [procès-verbal of rectification (Arabic text)].</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>At its 50th session, the General Assembly adopted, on 10 September 1996 by resolution &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_50_245-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/RES/50/245&lt;/a&gt; the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty as contained in document &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/A_RES_50_1027-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;A/50/1027&lt;/a&gt;. In the same resolution, the General Assembly requested the Secretary-General, as depositary of the Treaty, to open it for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York at the earliest possible date. The Treaty was opened for signature on 24 September 1996 and it will remain open for signature until its entry into force, in accordance with article XI.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
