<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>13</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>b</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Amendment to the Convention on Access to Information, Public Participation in Decision-Making and Access to Justice in Environmental Matters</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Almaty, 27 May 2005</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Not yet in force</Label>
          <Labeltext>in accordance with article 14(4) which stipulates: "Amendments to [the] Convention other than those to an annex shall enter into force for Parties having ratified, approved or accepted them on the ninetieth day after receipt by the Depositary of notification of their ratification, approval or acceptance by at least three fourths of these Parties. Thereafter they shall enter into force for any other Party on the ninetieth day after that Party deposits its instrument of ratification, approval or acceptance of the amendments.".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration />
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>31</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>&lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/Annex-to-the report-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt;Annex to the Report of the Second Meeting of the Parties (Decision II/1)&lt;/a&gt;.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>At the second meeting of the Parties to the above Convention, held in Almaty, Kazakhstan, from 25-27 May 2005, the Parties adopted, in accordance with the procedure laid down in article 14 (4) of the Convention on Access to Information, Public Participation in Decision-Making and Access to Justice in Environmental Matters, the Amendment to the said Convention as set out in the Annex to the Report of the Second Meeting of the Parties (Decision II/1).</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
