<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>15</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Stockholm, 22 May 2001</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>17 May 2004, in accordance with article 26(1) which reads as follows: "1. This Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit of the fiftieth instrument of ratification acceptance, approval or accession. 2. For each State or regional economic integration organization that ratifies, accepts or approves this Convention or accedes thereto after the deposit of the fiftieth instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession, the Convention shall enter into force on the ninetieth day after the date of deposit by such State or regional economic integration organization of its instrument of rafification, acceptance, approval or accession. 3. For the purpose of paragraphs 1 and 2, any instrument deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of that organization".</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>17 May 2004, No. 40214</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>152</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>182</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series&lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2256, p. 119; </Text>
          <Text>Depositary notifications: C.N.531.2001.TREATIES-96 of 19 June 2001; </Text>
          <Text>C.N.1204.2002.TREATIES-63 of 19 November 2002 [Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Convention (authentic Spanish text)] and C.N.157.2003.TREATIES-6 of 21 February 2003 [Correction of the original text of the Convention (authentic Spanish text)]; C.N.242.2006.TREATIES-6 of 27 March 2006 [Adoption of Annex G] and C.N.1017.2007.TREATIES-14 of 31 October 2007 [Entry into force of Annex G]; C.N.618.2007.TREATIES-12 of 5 June 2007 [Proposal of corrections to the original text of the Convention (authentic Russian text) and to the Certified True Copies]; C.N.524.2009.TREATIES-4 of 26 August 2009 [Adoption of Amendments to Annexes A, B and C] and C.N.546.2010.TREATIES-7 of 27 August 2010 [Entry into force of amendments to Annexes A, B and C] re-issued on 11 January 2011&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;;</Text>
          <Text>C.N.811.2011.TREATIES-10 of 31 January 2012 (Proposal of corrections to the Chinese text of Amendments to Annexes A, B and C) and C.N.219.2012.TREATIES-XXVII.15 of 1 May 2012 (Corrections to the Chinese text of Amendments to Annexes A, B and C); C.N.703.2011.TREATIES-8 [Adoption of an amendment to Annex A] of 27 October 2011 and C.N.762.2012.Reissued.18072014.TREATIES-XXVII.15 of 8 October 2013 (Entry into force)&lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt;; C.N.934.2013.TREATIES-XXVII-15 of 26 November 2013 (Amendment to Annex A) and C.N.738.2014.TREATIES-XXVII-15 of 2 December 2014 (Entry Into Force)&lt;superscript&gt;4&lt;/superscript&gt;; C.N.681.2015.TREATIES-XXVII-15 of 15 December 2015 (Amendments to Annexes A and C) and C.N.968.2016.TREATIES-XXVII-15 of 27 December 2016 (Entry into force of Amendments to Annexes A and C)&lt;superscript&gt;5&lt;/superscript&gt;; C.N.766.2017.TREATIES-XXVII-15 of 18 December 2017 (Amendments to Annexes A and C).</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted on 22 May 2001 at the Conference of Plenipotentiaries on the Stockholm Convention on Persistent Organic Pollutants, Stockholm, 22-23 May 2001. </Text>
          <Text>In accordance with its article 24, the Convention opened for signature at Stockholm by all States and by regional economic integration organizations on 23 May 2001 at the Stockholm City Conference Centre/Folkets Hus, and at the United Nations Headquarters in New York from 24 May 2001 to 22 May 2002.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
