<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>1</Numsect>
        <Subnumsect>d</Subnumsect>
        <Subtitlesect>Protocol to the 1979 Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution concerning the Control of Emissions of Volatile Organic Compounds or their Transboundary Fluxes</Subtitlesect>
        <Conclusion>Geneva, 18 November 1991</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>29 September 1997, in accordance with article 16(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>29 September 1997, No. 34322</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>23</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>24</Parties>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, Treaty Series, vol. 2001, p. 187.</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Protocol was drawn up within the framework of the Economic Commission for Europe and was adopted on 18 November 1991 by the Executive Body for the Convention on Long-Range Transboundary Air Pollution. It was opened for signature at the United Nations Office at Geneva from 18 to 19 November 1991 and thereafter at the Headquarters of the United Nations in New York until 22 May 1992.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="3">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Ratification, Acceptance(A), Approval(AA), Accession(a)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Austria</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>23 Aug 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belgium</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Nov 2000</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Bulgaria</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>27 Feb 1998</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Canada</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Croatia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>3 Mar 2008 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Czechia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>1 Jul 1997 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Denmark&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 1996 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Estonia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>7 Mar 2000 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>European Union</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Apr 1992</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Finland</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Jan 1994 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>France</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>12 Jun 1997 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Germany</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Dec 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Greece</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Hungary</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>10 Nov 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Italy</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>30 Jun 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Liechtenstein</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Mar 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lithuania</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>22 May 2007 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Luxembourg</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>11 Nov 1993</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Monaco</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>26 Jul 2001 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Netherlands&lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Sep 1993 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Norway</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>7 Jan 1993</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Portugal</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Apr 1992</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Slovakia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>15 Dec 1999 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Spain</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Feb 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sweden</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Jan 1993</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Switzerland</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>21 Mar 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>10 Mar 2010 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Ukraine</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland&lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry>14 Jun 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United States of America</Entry>
                <Entry>19 Nov 1991</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations made under article 2 (2)</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations were made</Title>
      <Title>upon ratification, acceptance, approval or accession.)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Austria</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature and confirmed upon ratification:</text>
        <text type="para">"With regard to article 2 (basic obligations) Austria declares to be bound by the provisions of paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;). Furthermore, Austria chooses the year 1988 as a base year with respect to paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Belgium</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">Belgium undertakes to reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30 per cent by the year 1999, using 1988 levels as a basis (article 2, paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)).</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Bulgaria</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature and confirmed upon ratification:</text>
        <text type="para">"Bulgaria declares under article 2, paragraph 2, sub-paragraph ( &lt;i&gt;c &lt;/i&gt;) that it shall, as soon as possible and as a first step, take effective measures to ensure at least that at the latest by the year 1999 its national annual emissions of VOCs do not exceed the 1988 levels."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Canada</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Pursuant to article 2, paragraph 2 of the Protocol, Canada is pleased to inform other Parties to the present Protocol that it selects option ( &lt;i&gt;b &lt;/i&gt;) from among the three options available. Base year: 1988."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Czechia</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration :</text>
        <text type="para">"[The Government of the Czech Republic] declares that it shall use the 1990 levels as the basis for its reduction of annual emissions of VOCs pursuant to article 2, paragraph 2( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;) of the Protocol."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Denmark</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Denmark hereby declares that it will reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30% by the year 1999, using 1985 as a basis.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>European Union</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"The European Economic community, taking account in particular of the alternatives available to its Member States in application of Article 2 (2) of the Protocol, hereby declares that its obligations under the Protocol with regard to the objectives for reducing VOC emissions may not be greater than the sum of the obligations entered into by its Member States which have ratified the Protocol."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Finland</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Finland declares that it intends to reduce its annual national emissions of VOCs by at least 30%, using 1988 levels as a basis."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>France</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature and confirmed upon approval:</text>
        <text type="para">The French Republic undertakes to reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30 per cent by the year 1999, using 1988 levels as a basis (article 2, paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)).</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Germany</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Germany specifies that it shall reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30% by the year 1999 using 1988 levels as a basis according to article 2, paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Greece</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Greece declares under article 2, paragraph 2, sub-paragraph c) that it shall, as soon as possible and as a first step, take effective measures to ensure at least that at the latest by the year 1999 its national annual emissions of VOCs do not exceed the 1988 levels."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Hungary</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Republic of Hungary shall control and reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs or their transboundary fluxes in accordance with the provisions of paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;c &lt;/i&gt;) of article 2 of the Protocol."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Italy</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Italy declares its intention to meet the requirements of article 2.1 of the Protocol in the way specified at article 2, paragraph 2, letter ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;) and its intention to indicate as reference year as a basis for reduction: 1990."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Liechtenstein</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"As a basis to reduce its annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30% by the year 1999, Liechtenstein will use 1984 levels."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Luxembourg</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">Luxembourg undertakes to reduce its national annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30 per cent by the year 1999, using 1990 levels as a basis (article 2, paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)).</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Monaco</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration :</text>
        <text type="para">The Government of the Principality of Monaco shall reduce its emissions of VOCs by 30% during the year 2001, using 1990 levels as a basis.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Netherlands</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature and confirmed upon acceptance:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Netherlands declares that it intends to reduce its annual national emissions of VOCs by at least 30% using 1988 levels as a basis."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Norway</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Government of Norway intends to fulfil the obligations of the VOC Protocol as specified in article 2, paragraph 2 (b). Norway will use the year 1989 as the base year for reductions.</text>
        <text type="para">Based on present prognosis of VOC emissions the total Norwegian reduction of VOC will be in the order of 20% by the year 1999.</text>
        <text type="para">"Norway will apply equivalent measures based on the best available technologies which are economically feasible, outside the TOMA as inside.</text>
        <text type="para">"The Government of Norway will fulfil its obligations in the Exclusive Economic Zone of Norway under the Protocol in conformity with international law."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Portugal</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Portugal declares under its article 2, paragraph 2, sub-paragraph &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;), that is shall control and reduce its national annual emissions of VOC's or their transboundary fluxes in accordance with the way specified at that article."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Slovakia</Participant>
        <text type="para">... the Slovak Republic specifies the year 1990 as the base year for purposes of the Protocol.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Spain</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">The Government of the Kingdom of Spain declares that it accepts the commitment set forth in article 2 [(2)] ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;) to reduce national annual emissions by at least 30 per cent by the year 1999, using 1988 levels as a basis.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Sweden</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"Sweden declares that it intends to reduce its annual national emissions of VOCs by at least 30%, using 1988 levels as a basis."</text>
        <text type="title">Upon ratification:</text>
        <text type="para">"Sweden declares that it intends to reduce its annual national emissions of VOCs by at least 30% by the year 1999, using 1988 levels as a basis."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Switzerland</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"As a basis to reduce its annual emissions of VOCs by at least 30% by the year 1999, Switzerland will use 1984 levels."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Ukraine</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">[The Government of Ukraine] signs [the said Protocol] on the conditions set out in paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;b &lt;/i&gt;) of article 2 of the Protocol.</text>
        <text type="para">In so doing the Government of Ukraine stipulates that the following designated tropospheric ozone management areas (TOMAs) situated in Ukraine should be included in Annex I to the Protocol:</text>
        <text type="para">TOMA No. 1: the Poltavian, Dnepropetrovsk, Zaporozhian, Donetsk, Lugantsk, Nikolaivian, Khersonian regions (194.3 thousand square kilometres);</text>
        <text type="para">TOMA No. 2: Lvovian, Ternopol, Ivano-Frankovsk, Zakarpatian regions (62.3 thousand square kilometres).</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration made upon signature and confirmed upon ratification:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland declares] that it intends to reduce its annual national emissions of VOCs by at least 30%, using 1988 levels as a basis."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>United States of America</Participant>
        <text type="title">Upon signature:</text>
        <text type="para">"In accordance with article 2, paragraph 2 of the Protocol, the Government of the United States of America specifies 1984 emission levels as the basis for its VOC reductions under this Protocol [article 2, paragraph 2 ( &lt;i&gt;a &lt;/i&gt;)]".</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="YES" />
    <EndNotes>
      <Note>
        <index>1</index>
        <text>Upon signature, decision was reserved as concerns the application of the Protocol to the Faroe Islands and Greenland. Upon acceptance, the Government of Denmark declared that "This acceptance does not apply to the Faroe Islands and Greenland.".</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>2</index>
        <text>For the Kingdom in Europe.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>3</index>
        <text>Application to the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, the Bailiwick of Guernsey, the Bailiwick of Jersey and the Isle of Man.</text>
      </Note>
    </EndNotes>
    <Footer>XXVII 1 d. Environment</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
