<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<Document>
  <Treaty>
    <Template>mtdsg</Template>
    <Header>
      <Chapter>
        <Header>CHAPTER XXVII</Header>
        <Name>ENVIRONMENT</Name>
      </Chapter>
      <ExternalData>
        <Numsect>6</Numsect>
        <Titlesect>Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents</Titlesect>
        <Conclusion>Helsinki, 17 March 1992</Conclusion>
        <EIF>
          <Label>Entry into force</Label>
          <Labeltext>19 April 2000, in accordance with article 30(1).</Labeltext>
        </EIF>
        <Registration>
          <Label>Registration</Label>
          <Labeltext>19 April 2000, No. 36605</Labeltext>
        </Registration>
        <Status>
          <Label>Status</Label>
          <SignatoriesLabel>Signatories</SignatoriesLabel>
          <Signatories>27</Signatories>
          <PartiesLabel>Parties</PartiesLabel>
          <Parties>41</Parties>
          <Notes>
            <Note>1</Note>
          </Notes>
        </Status>
        <TreatyText>
          <Label>Text</Label>
          <Text>United Nations, &lt;i&gt;Treaty Series &lt;/i&gt;, vol. 2105, p. 457.</Text>
          <Text>Doc.&lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/ECE_CP.TEIA_15_Add.1-E.pdf" target="_blank"&gt; ECE/CP.TEIA/15/Add.1&lt;/a&gt; (Amendements to Annex I of Convention) &lt;superscript&gt;2&lt;/superscript&gt; Doc. &lt;a href="/doc/source/docs/ECE_CP.TEIA_30_Add.1-E.pdf " target="_blank"&gt; ECE/CP.TEIA/30/Add.1&lt;/a&gt; (Decision 2014/2 Amending Annex I to the Convention) &lt;superscript&gt;3&lt;/superscript&gt;</Text>
        </TreatyText>
        <TreatyNote>
          <Text>The Convention was adopted by the Senior Advisers to the Economic Commission for Europe Governments on Environmental and Water Problems at their Resumed Fifth Session held at Helsinki from 17 to 18 March 1992. The Convention was opened for signature at Helsinki from 17 to 18 March 1992 and was open for signature at United Nations Headquarters in New York until 18 September 1992.</Text>
        </TreatyNote>
      </ExternalData>
    </Header>
    <Participants>
      <Table colsep="0" frame="none" rowsep="0">
        <TGroup cols="3">
          <Thead>
            <Row rowsep="0">
              <Entry colname="1">Participant</Entry>
              <Entry colname="2">Signature</Entry>
              <Entry colname="3">Ratification, Accession(a), Acceptance(A), Approval(AA)</Entry>
            </Row>
          </Thead>
          <Tbody>
            <Rows>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Albania</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>5 Jan 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Armenia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>21 Feb 1997 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Austria</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>4 Aug 1999</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Azerbaijan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>16 Jun 2004 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belarus</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>25 Jun 2003 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Belgium</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Apr 2006</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Bosnia and Herzegovina</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>20 Feb 2013 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Bulgaria</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>12 May 1995</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Canada</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Croatia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>20 Jan 2000 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Cyprus</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>31 Aug 2005 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Czech Republic</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>12 Jun 2000 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Denmark&lt;superscript&gt;4&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>28 Mar 2001 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Estonia</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>17 May 2000</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>European Union&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Apr 1998 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Finland</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>13 Sep 1999 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>France</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>3 Oct 2003 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Germany</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Sep 1998</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Greece</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>24 Feb 1998</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Hungary</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Jun 1994 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Italy</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Jul 2002</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Kazakhstan</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>11 Jan 2001 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Latvia</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>29 Jun 2004</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Lithuania</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Nov 2000</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Luxembourg</Entry>
                <Entry>20 May 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Aug 1994</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Monaco</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>28 Aug 2001 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Montenegro</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>19 May 2009 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Netherlands&lt;superscript&gt;5&lt;/superscript&gt;</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>6 Nov 2006 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Norway</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Sep 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Apr 1993 AA</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Poland</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>8 Sep 2003</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Portugal</Entry>
                <Entry>9 Jun 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>2 Nov 2006</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Republic of Moldova</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>4 Jan 1994 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Romania</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>22 May 2003 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Russian Federation</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>1 Feb 1994 A</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Serbia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>31 Jul 2009 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Slovakia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>9 Sep 2003 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Slovenia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>13 May 2002 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Spain</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>16 May 1997</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Sweden</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>22 Sep 1999</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>Switzerland</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>21 May 1999</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>The former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia</Entry>
                <Entry />
                <Entry>2 Mar 2010 a</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry>5 Aug 2002</Entry>
              </Row>
              <Row>
                <Entry>United States of America</Entry>
                <Entry>18 Mar 1992</Entry>
                <Entry />
              </Row>
            </Rows>
          </Tbody>
        </TGroup>
      </Table>
    </Participants>
    <SpecialTables />
    <Declarations>
      <Title>Declarations and Reservations</Title>
      <Title>(Unless otherwise indicated, the declarations and reservations were made</Title>
      <Title>upon ratification, accession, acceptance or approval.)</Title>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Austria</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Republic of Austria declares in accordance with article?1 paragraph 2 of the Convention to accept both of the means of the settlement of disputes mentioned in this paragraph as compulsory in relation to any Party accepting one or both of these means of settlement of disputes as compulsory."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Azerbaijan</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declarations:</text>
        <text type="para">"1. The Republic of Azerbaijan declares that the term military installations' appearing in article 2, paragraph 2 (b), of the Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents is understood to refer to installations serving the interests of national defence and functioning on legal causes.</text>
        <text type="para">2. With reference to article 3, paragraph 1, of the Convention, the Republic of Azerbaijan declares that, in relation to any Party, it will cooperate within the framework of the Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents in accordance with the principles and norms of international law.</text>
        <text type="para">3. In accordance with article 21, paragraph 2, of the Convention, the Republic of Azerbaijan declares that, for a dispute not resolved in accordance with paragraph 1 of article 21, it accepts the arbitration in accordance with the procedure set out in Annex XIII as compulsory in relation to any Party accepting one or both of the means of dispute settlement referred to in paragraph 2 of article 21."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>European Union&lt;superscript&gt;1&lt;/superscript&gt;</Participant>
        <text type="title">Reservations:</text>
        <text type="para">On 27 April 2007, the European Community informed the Secretary-General of its decision to withdraw the reservation made upon approval to the Convention (see United Nations, Treaty Series, vol. 2105, p. 575 for the text of the reservation) and replace it with the following reservation:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Member States of the European Community, in their mutual relations, will apply the Convention in accordance with the Community's internal rules. The Community therefore reserves the right as concerns the threshold quantities mentioned in Annex I, Part I, Nos. 4, 5, and 6 to the Convention, to apply threshold quantities of 100 tonnes for bromine (very toxic substance), 5000 tonnes for methanol (toxic substance) and 2000 tonnes for oxygen (oxidising substance)."</text>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">In accordance with the EC Treaty, the objectives and principles of the Communitys environmental policy are, in particular, to preserve and protect the quality of the environment and human health through preventive action. In pursuit of those objectives, the Council adopted Council Directive 82/501/EEC of 24 June 1982 on the major-accident hazards of certain industrial activities which has been replaced by Council Directive 96/82/EC of 9 December 1996 on the control of major-accident hazards involving dangerous substances. These instruments aim at the prevention of major-accident hazards involving dangerous substances and the limitations of their consequences for man and the environment and cover matters which are the subject of [the said Convention]. The Community will inform the depositary of any amendment to this Directive and of any further relevant development in the field covered by the Convention.</text>
        <text type="para">As regards the application of the Convention, the Community and its Member States are responsible, within their respective spheres of competence.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>France</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration and reservation:</text>
        <text type="para">1. Interpretative declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">The French Government declares that the term "military installations" appearing in article 2, paragraph 2 (b), of the Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents is understood to refer to installations serving the interests of national defence and to weapons systems and nuclear-powered vessels of the national navy.</text>
        <text type="para">2. Reservation:</text>
        <text type="para">At the time of adopting the Convention on the Transboundary Effects of Industrial Accidents, signed at Helsinki on 18 March 1992, the French Republic associates itself with the reservations expressed by the European Community at the time of the deposit of its instrument of ratification and states that it will apply the Convention in accordance with its obligations under Directive 96/82 of the Council of the European Union of 9 December 1996 on the control of major-accident hazards involving dangerous substances.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Hungary</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Government of the Republic of Hungary accepts both means of dispute settlement as compulsory in relation to any Party accepting the same obligation."</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Netherlands</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">"The Kingdom of the Netherlands accepts, for a dispute not resolved in accordance with paragraph 1 of Article 21 of the Convention, both means of dispute settlement mentioned in this paragraph as compulsory in relation to any Party accepting the same obligation.</text>
        <text type="title">Reservation:</text>
        <text type="para">The Kingdom of the Netherlands reserves the right as concerns the threshold quantities mentioned in Annex I of the Convention, to apply the threshold quantities mentioned in European Council Directive 96/82/EC of 9 December 1996 on the control of major-accident hazards involving dangerous substances.</text>
        <text type="para" />
      </Declaration>
      <Declaration>
        <Participant>Serbia</Participant>
        <text type="title">Declaration:</text>
        <text type="para">The Republic of Serbia declares in accordance with article 21 paragaph 2 of the Convention that it accepts submission of the dispute to the International Court of Justice, mentioned in paragraph 2 (a).</text>
      </Declaration>
    </Declarations>
    <Objections />
    <DeclarationsUnderArticle />
    <Notifications />
    <TerritorialApplications show="YES" />
    <EndNotes>
      <Note>
        <index>1</index>
        <text>For the purpose of entry into force of the [Convention/Protocol] , any instrument of ratification, acceptance, approval or accession deposited by a regional economic integration organization shall not be counted as additional to those deposited by member States of that Organization.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>2</index>
        <text>The Amendments were adopted at the fourth meeting of the Conference of the Parties, held in Rome from 15 to 17 November 2006 and entered into force for all Parties to the Convention on 19 March 2008.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>3</index>
        <text>The Amendments were adopted at the eighth meeting of the Conference of the Parties, held in Geneva from 3 to 5 December 2014 and entered into force for all Parties to the Convention on 19 December 2015.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>4</index>
        <text>With reservation of application to the Faroe Islands and Greenland.</text>
      </Note>
      <Note>
        <index>5</index>
        <text>For the Kingdom in Europe.</text>
      </Note>
    </EndNotes>
    <Footer>XXVII 6. Environment</Footer>
  </Treaty>
</Document>
